- Bow!
- [grunts]
- Einstein wasn't right about everything.
- [softly] Hmm.
If anyone can figure this out, it's you.
- Saul.
- Yeah?
[haunting orchestral music playing]
Do you believe in God?
Is that what it's come to?
No. I don't.
I accept that this defies
all known laws of physics,
but... I don't think
that's an argument for God.
So, what's left?
[haunting strings building]
- [door opens]
- [sensors humming]
[door closes]
[mechanical droning reverberates]
[inhales sharply]
[music builds to a terrifying crescendo]
- ["I Kissed a Girl" playing]
- ♪ I kissed a girl, and I liked it ♪
♪ The taste of her cherry ChapStick
I kissed... ♪
- [quietly] Wow.
- Confidence.
- You know you're carrying me home, right?
- I've done it before.
[both] Salud.
[mouthing] Thank you.
[out of tune]
♪ I kissed a girl, and I liked it... ♪
It's possible our bar has gone to shit.
Second law of thermodynamics.
Eventually, everything turns to shit.
Physics is turning to shit.
Bars can't be far behind.
Explain to me what's going on.
Okay...
So, you ladies are gonna sing a song?
- No.
- [man] No? What do you mean, no?
You're not... not singers?
- No.
- [man chuckles] All right.
What do you do, then? Hmm?
Wait. Hold on. Don't tell me.
Let me guess. You probably...
I design self-assembling,
synthetic polymer nanofibers.
I started a company that manufactures them
for a variety of potential medical,
energy, and materials applications.
And you?
I'm a senior researcher
in the Theoretical Physics group
at Imperial College.
I'm doing a metastudy
analyzing the results
of particle accelerator experiments
around the world.
Nice one. Yeah.
- [MC] Rufus, you're up!
- [Rufus] Yeah, all right. That's me!
Yeah, enjoy it. Bye.
Okay, why is everyone freaking out?
[sighs]
About a month ago,
all the major accelerators
started generating results
that make no fucking sense.
- ♪ It's nine o'clock on a Saturday ♪
- [crowd cheers]
♪ And the regular crowd shuffles in ♪
♪ There's an old man sitting next to me ♪
♪ Making love to his tonic and gin ♪
[vocalizing]
Go on, you know it!
Come have a smoke with me.
- That shit'll kill you.
- Yeah. So will this.
[Rufus] ♪ Play me a memory? ♪
- ["Take on Me" playing]
- ♪ I don't know what I'm to say ♪
♪ I'll say it anyway... ♪
Wow.
[Jin] Mm.
Saul sent that one
just last week from Oxford.
It's been a while since Particle Physics,
but, I mean, this can't...
Nope. It can't.
- Well, then, maybe it's a hack.
- [scoffs]
In every accelerator on the planet?
I went through the CERN code,
line by line. Nothing.
The code for the centralized software?
How many lines is that?
It's a lot, Auggie.
It's a lot of fucking lines.
Okay, so it's a hardware issue.
Dipole magnets,
muon chambers, calorimeters,
every component checked four times over
in every collider from here to Beijing.
Okay, so what does Saul say?
He says it's impossible.
What about you?
[sighs] These experiments teach us
how the universe works.
And that?
That's fucking
Alice in Wonderland. [clicks tongue]
[cell phone ringing]
Now he calls.
I texted him to come three times,
and he wouldn't even text me back.
[scoffs]
[energy thrumming]
See how you like it.
- You guys are like 14-year-olds.
- [sighs]
[cell phone beeps]
[Auggie chuckles]
Take it. He's probably high as fuck.
It's fine. Take it.
[Jin] Hey.
[exhales deeply]
[tense music playing]
[lighter clicks]
- Hey.
- Oh. Hey, hi.
[softly] Do you see that?
See what?
- That.
- Huh?
[gasps softly]
[Rufus] You all right, love?
[inhales sharply]
[energy thrumming]
[breathing shakily]
- [Jin] Auggie?
- [gasps]
Vera Ye just killed herself.
[cap snaps on marker]
[birds singing]
- [indistinct chatter outside]
- [water running]
Excited to see Jin?
Well, it's not exactly
ideal circumstances, is it?
How long has it been?
Don't know.
I'll bet you do.
I bet you remember to the day.
It's been a while.
Fuck. I did not sleep at all last night.
Why not?
[inhales sharply]
I don't know, Jack. Maybe it's, uh...
Maybe it's because Vera's killed herself.
[Jack sighs]
[unscrews cap]
To Vera.
[gulps]
- [flask clatters]
- [rustling]
- Jesus.
- Hm?
[scoffs]
Hides the tequila smell.
- Want one?
- No.
- Have one.
- I don't want one.
It's my most popular flavor.
Third highest-selling crisps in the UK
after Walkers Cheese and Onion
and Monster Munch Beef.
- Congratulations.
- Mm-hmm. Suck a dick, Pringles.
- [chuckles]
- [Jack sniffles]
[fastens flask cap]
Have you heard
that Jin's got a new boyfriend?
Don't worry.
I bet he's a total squid.
[church bells tolling]
You okay?
[crows cawing in distance]
[Jin chuckles] Fuckin' Saul.
Come say hi.
[Jin] So sorry.
[Saul] Yeah. Me too.
So, this is Prithviraj.
Just Raj, mate.
Nice to meet you. [clears throat]
- [Jin] What is goin' on here?
- I was trying to figure it out on YouTube.
Winner of the Apker Award.
Can't tie a tie.
Well, Lord Kelvin thought that
atoms were knotted vortices in the ether.
- Ah, did he?
- He also thought that there are... [coughs]
Thank you.
[Jin] Is Auggie here yet?
[Saul] She said she's running late.
- [train clattering on tracks]
- [horn blares]
[indistinct chatter]
[woman on PA] This service
is now approaching Oxford,
where this train will terminate.
Please make sure
you have all your belongings with you
before you leave the train.
[breathing shakily]
[gasps]
[energy thrumming]
[inhales sharply]
[takes a deep breath]
- [thrumming intensifies]
- [glowing numbers sizzling]
[thrumming fades]
[monks chanting]
[Jin] So sorry for your loss.
We all loved your daughter very much.
Thank you for coming.
[chanting continues]
[Vera's mom] You've all been so kind.
Jin's looking good.
Phwoar. He's looking good as well.
- What?
- Fuck off.
[Jin sighs]
- [Jack chuckles softly]
- [door opens]
[both] Hey.
[sighs] How are you doing?
Yeah, you know...
[sighs softly, sniffles]
- [Raj mouthing]
- [Auggie] Hey.
[inhales sharply]
[whispers] Did you see the neurologist?
[quietly] Yeah.
What'd he say?
- She.
- She. Oh. Jesus.
She has no clue why it's happening.
Well, still. It's still happening?
- [door opens]
- Like, right now?
- Like, all the fucking time.
- [door closes]
- [sighs]
- [footsteps approach]
[tense instrumental music playing]
[chanting intensifies]
[temple block tapping]
[mala beads rattling]
- [breathing shakily]
- [sounds distort]
- [energy thrumming]
- [menacing music playing]
- [music cuts out]
- [man] You drove, right?
- [indistinct chatter]
- [camera shutter clicking rapidly]
[tense, energetic music playing]
[lens whirs]
- [shutter clicking rapidly]
- [brakes squeak]
[tense music building]
[engine revs]
[tires squeal]
[lens whirs]
[camera shutter clicking rapidly]
[investigator exhales]
[whirring of blades fades into distance]
[Jin] What does that even mean?
"Do you believe in God?"
Strange question, don't you think?
Yeah. Not as strange as jumping
into a Cherenkov tank, but sure.
Was she acting weird, or...
I don't know. Uh, yes?
But everything has been weird lately.
[Jin] That project was her baby.
When it was shut down, it was like...
[Jack] It was shut down?
Can't justify using enough electricity
to power a small town
when you're getting nonsense results.
Yeah. Not just Oxford.
Every major accelerator on the planet.
[Will] She must've been depressed
about that.
[Saul] Yeah. But to kill yourself?
She was a bit of a killjoy,
if we're being honest.
Don't be a dick, Jack.
Ah. No. Listen to him.
You were her favorite.
She'd have happily kept you on as
a research assistant till the end of time.
But the rest of us, good luck.
That's fucking rich,
considering you're the one who quit.
And trust me,
all of you fucking noble academics,
you'll be coming to me
and Auggie for loans in a few years.
- Oh, fuck off.
- [sighs]
Isn't that right, Auggie? When your...
When your company goes public?
["The Killing Moon"
by Echo & the Bunnymen playing]
- Auggie!
- [Auggie sighs]
♪ Nights I saw you... ♪
We're just saying that...
What did you call your company?
Uh, the Nanotechnology Research Center.
That's probably
the most boring name I've ever heard.
[Jin] Oh! Says the guy who named
his company "Jack's Snacks."
- [Auggie] Yeah.
- Don't be a dick.
Will, how's, uh... How's teaching going?
[hesitates] Uh, I don't know.
Like, I have about, um...
one kid in every class
who actually listens to what I'm saying.
And the rest are just there
for their mandatory science course.
- [Jin] Oh.
- We were all that one kid.
Yeah, that's true. [sighs]
Are you two fighting right now?
- Or fucking?
- [group murmurs]
- [Saul chuckles]
- [Auggie clears throat]
Oh! Fighting and fucking.
- [Auggie] Jack!
- Stop.
Shut your mouth. You wanna know as well.
Jack, I love you, but I swear,
if you don't shut the fuck up,
I'm gonna punch a hole
straight through your head.
["The Killing Moon" continues]
I'm just gonna grab a cigarette.
[excited chatter]
[panting]
[dogs barking in distance]
[truck engine putters by]
[quietly] Oh shit.
[sighs]
[wind whistling]
[flip-top lighter clicks]
[woman] Need a little help?
[Auggie] Thank you.
[exhales]
[woman sighs]
May I?
[Auggie] Hmm.
[exhales]
It's a clear night.
- [energy thrumming]
- [woman] You can see the stars.
Where I grew up,
you could see the stars every night.
It's not easy, is it?
Being a person in this fucked world.
- I understand what you're going through.
- [sighs]
[scoffs] I doubt it.
It's not hopeless, though.
[Auggie sighs]
- Really.
- [clears throat]
The Lord has a better way.
[sighs] Listen, you seem
like a very nice person.
I'm just not interested, okay?
How far has it got?
Your countdown?
[unsettling string music playing]
How much time do you have left?
- [gasps]
- Less than two days?
Yeah?
That's not much.
It's easy to make it stop.
You put an end to your work.
No more nanofibers.
You shut down the lab.
Simple.
- Who are you?
- I'd be suspicious as well.
Tell you what.
Tomorrow, at midnight,
at exactly midnight,
go outside and look up at the sky.
Has the universe ever winked at you?
[ominous tone resonates]
[woman] Tomorrow at midnight.
You don't want it to get to zero.
Nothing good ever happens at zero.
[footsteps fade]
[Auggie] Hey!
[ominous tones building]
[energy thrumming]
- [tones fade]
- [wood creaking]
- [bird calls]
- [trunk strains]
[men grunting]
- [indistinct chatter]
- [somber music playing]
[workers panting]
[foreman shouting orders in Mandarin]
[all groaning]
[Ye Wenjie grunts]
[foreman shouting]
[indistinct chatter]
[man in Mandarin] How old?
Between three and four hundred, I assume.
[man] That tree saw the Ming emperors.
You must have considered
the consequences of all this destruction.
These thoughts are dangerous.
I have nothing to say
to the Great Production News.
I'm not asking on behalf of the paper.
I'm just Bai Mulin,
fellow comrade.
[alarm blaring above]
[dish whirs]
I've climbed up there. No one knows
what goes on behind those gates.
Things get odder the closer you get.
The soldiers working there
have lost their hair.
Clear weather turns stormy.
The animals make strange sounds.
[wind picks up]
[softly] You read English, don't you?
Silent Spring.
This book was very influential
in the West.
It's about how people
are poisoning the world.
It's like reading into the future
if we persist with this destruction.
[melancholic piano music playing]
[in English] "Here again, we are reminded
that in nature, nothing exists alone."
[in Mandarin]
Keep it for now if you want to read it.
But be careful.
Don't let anyone see.
- [wind gusting]
- [thunder rumbling]
[worker coughing]
[rain pattering on roof]
- [tools clanging]
- [indistinct chatter]
[gentle orchestral music playing]
[branches creaking in breeze]
[guards chatting in distance]
[both breathing heavily]
[Ye Wenjie grunts]
[gentle music swells]
[tools clanging in distance]
[gentle music fades]
[music grows tense]
[gasps]
[music fades out]
[panting]
[inhales sharply]
Commander Song. Forgive me.
I didn't see where I was going.
[tense music playing]
[wind whistling]
Have you lost this?
How did you get this toxic propaganda?
It isn't mine.
It's in English.
You speak English. Who else's could it be?
A truthful response
is in your best interest.
I forget.
[Song] You will pay the price
if you are protecting someone.
Someone must have given it to you!
Take her to Division Headquarters.
[somber music playing]
[engine running]
[wind whistling]
[woman] I am Teng Lihua
of the Intermediate People's Court.
How long have they made you wait?
[Teng Lihua] Boy.
How long has this stove been out?
Little Wenjie will freeze to death!
Fetch some coal.
[footsteps fade]
I asked to see you. Do you know why?
[door closes]
Because not only are you the daughter
of the disgraced Ye Zhetai,
but his star pupil as well.
In the eyes of many in the Party,
this makes you irredeemable.
But I don't see it that way.
I know of your own accomplishments
as a scholar.
I don't want your talent to go to waste.
All you need to do is sign this paper,
take a political class,
and you'll be approved
to rejoin the Construction Corps.
I'd like to read it, please.
[sighs, takes a deep breath]
You can trust me on this.
This document has nothing to do
with the Imperialist book.
[breathing shakily]
My father is dead.
But there are others in his field
still spreading dangerous ideas.
We lack evidence against them.
I've never seen my father
with any of these people.
The statements are all true.
Even your mother has signed.
See.
I cannot sign this.
I cannot testify.
If you fail to sign,
the Military Control Commission
will prosecute you.
At that stage,
I will be powerless to help.
- [tense music playing]
- [papers rustle]
I cannot sign this.
I cannot testify.
- [shivering]
- [bucket clatters]
[under breath] Stubborn little bitch.
[cell door slams]
[haunting orchestral music playing]
[rattling]
[speaking softly in Mandarin]
[music fades]
- [birds singing]
- [wind gusting]
Ye Wenjie.
I am Lei Zhicheng,
Political Commissar of Red Coast Base.
This is Yang Weining,
Chief Engineer of Red Coast Base.
Ye Wenjie, you are credited
as the author of this article.
Yes.
[in English] "The Possible Extenses of..."
"The Possible Existence
of Phase Boundaries
within the Solar Radiation Zone
and Their Reflective Characteristics."
[in Mandarin] Yes. I wrote it.
We have a need for your specific talents.
The Commission has decided
to give you a chance.
Rehabilitate yourself here
rather than prison.
This is a military base.
The research here
is of the highest security classification.
And given your status,
if you stay,
you will never leave.
I want to go in.
[tense music playing]
I will stay here for the rest of my life.
[doors close heavily]
- [birds calling]
- [car horn honks in distance]
[takes a deep breath]
[cell phone vibrating]
[sighs]
Yep.
- [Wade on speakerphone] Any progress?
- More than you think. Less than you want.
Anything happening with the Oxford five?
Maybe. Some strange CCTV footage
on Salazar the night of Vera Ye's funeral.
What about Evans?
[clicks tongue] Rarely seen
in public since 1984.
Next to nothing written about him
for 42 years
since he took over daddy's oil company.
Where'd he go in that helicopter?
We lost him over the Atlantic.
Satellite malfunction.
My satellites don't malfunction.
All right. Now,
what about that thing in Tehran?
The shiny bicycle helmet?
Whatever it is,
we can't get our hands on it.
Are we sure it was another suicide?
I wouldn't say "sure."
The Iranians have been
less than completely helpful.
Clarence, you've been fired
from Scotland Yard, MI5, and OSCT.
That must be some kind of record.
I've got a knack for failing upwards.
You don't fail any higher than this.
This is your last-chance saloon.
Don't fuck it up.
No smoking in here.
[soothing piano music playing]
[birds singing outside]
[Vera's mom speaking Mandarin]
Take it. She would want you to have it.
[Jin] I don't understand it.
I've tried.
But I just can't wrap my head around it,
why she would do that.
That wasn't Vera.
Her work... Things weren't going well.
I know. It's the same for all of us.
I'm sorry to ask, but did she leave
a note or any explanation?
[softly] Nothing.
She asked Saul about God.
Did she ever ask you?
About God?
We're not believers in this house.
We're scientists.
Did she say anything strange to you?
Did she do anything strange?
Video games.
- She was playing a video game.
- Vera?
Yes, quite a lot.
Hmm.
Where is it?
Oh.
[ominous music playing]
That's a video game?
Where's the rest of it?
That's it.
[Jin] What kind of game is this?
[quietly] I don't know. [chuckles]
I played Pong.
[both chuckle softly]
Can I have it?
Of course.
[music fades]
Is that you?
In another life. My first job.
You're beautiful.
I was.
Time is a motherfucker.
[suspenseful music playing]
[machinery whirring]
[Lei in Mandarin] Only three months,
and you get to see your first test.
You're lucky.
Most people have to wait longer.
What are we testing?
Missiles?
Everybody has missiles.
[man on PA] Target Coordinates: BN20197F,
checked and confirmed.
Test transmission in ten.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Begin transmission.
- [static crackling]
- [high-pitched ringing]
[wings fluttering]
[birds calling frantically]
[birds slamming against satellite dish]
[panicked chirping intensifies]
- [ringing fades]
- [flapping dies down]
[man on PA] Transmission complete.
[softly] BN20197F.
[somber music playing]
Those were the coordinates for the target.
You have a good memory.
What is the target?
[wind gusting]
[music fades]
[ominous music playing]
[sounds distort]
[muffled echoing]
[Jin gasps]
[woman] Level one.
[wind gusting]
[static crackles]
[Jin gasps]
[exhales sharply]
[sighs]
[ominous music playing]
[wind picks up]
[Jin grunting]
- [screams]
- [static crackles]
[breathing shakily]
What the fuck?
[Clarence] Wade really wants
one of these helmets.
Thinks they're highly relevant.
We ever seen one over here?
No, not yet.
What else is relevant?
Mike Evans.
That bicycle helmet looks expensive.
Evans is rich.
What about the countdowns?
Yes, if they happen to scientists.
Suicides, if they happen to scientists.
Anything strange happening
to scientists is relevant.
Anyone connected to anything strange
happening to scientists is relevant.
- Who decides what's relevant?
- Wade.
- Who decides he decides?
- Governments.
- [investigator] Which ones?
- Most.
They're not too keen on
the notion of science being broken.
I don't really understand
the science that's broken, to be honest.
I don't understand it either,
but it's not good.
[elevator bell chimes]
Just be glad you're not a scientist.
Shit time to be a scientist.
- [crickets chirping]
- [Auggie] You're smoking a lot of weed.
Yep. Is that why we're here?
This an intervention?
[Auggie] No.
- Well, what are we doing here?
- Not what you're thinking.
- I don't think anything.
- Yeah, you are. And it's not that.
You asked me to come, here I am,
on this moonless night,
in this beautiful place.
[in Spanish] You with all those curves
and me with no brakes.
[groans]
[exhales, in English] What did
that weird chick say to you again?
"Has the universe ever winked at you?"
She said to look at the sky at midnight
and gave me this.
[decoder clicks]
[Auggie] It came out of
a breakfast cereal. I looked it up.
They haven't made it since 1963.
- What's going on with you, though?
- I don't want you to know.
No confirmation bias.
Just watch, and let me know what
you observe, if you observe anything.
Science, dude.
That's why you're here, okay?
I understand my role. [clears throat]
Thank you for being here.
[Saul clears throat]
[clicking]
[Saul] It looks like Morse code,
but it's not.
- You know Morse code?
- I know all kind of shit.
Toasty-O-Sters.
I mean, it's not a very good name.
I could think of a better name.
I'd have to taste it first.
The name should reflect and support
what it feels like to eat the cereal.
It's toasted. Like, we know that much...
Shut up and observe.
Two minutes to midnight. [sighs]
[tense music playing]
[machinery whirring]
[in Mandarin] Sit.
Not everyone here agrees
with what is about to be done.
Given your political status.
On Chief Engineer Yang's recommendation,
we have decided
to inform you of the true nature
of the Red Coast Project.
[grunts] Stars are so bright tonight.
You're so high.
Yeah, but still,
they're pretty bright.
- [Auggie gasps]
- [bell tolling the hour]
[ominous orchestral music playing]
Saul.
[breathing shakily]
[quietly] Oh my God.
[in Mandarin] Red Coast is not
an experimental weapons program.
Go on.
The emissions from the system
are modulated.
Frequency modulation is not necessary
for weapons systems.
You are correct.
It is not necessary for weaponization.
But it is necessary for communication.
[bell continues tolling the hour]
[ominous music building]
[low rumbling]
[Saul] I observe the universe winking.
How can it be happening?
It can't.
[panting]
Shit. It's a code.
What?
[decoder clicking]
[Auggie] What does it say?
What does it say?
[in Mandarin] Communication...
with whom?
With whomever is out there.
[Clarence] What is that? [sighs]
That, Clarence, is our enemy.
It's not letters. It's just numbers.
Which numbers?
[Saul] Ten, thirty-four, zero, six,
five, four, three,
two, one.
[ominous music fades]
[tense music playing]
[clock ticking]
[Clarence] Don't you want to know
why the stars flickered for you?
[Jin] This is what Vera was playing
before she killed herself.
[man] Your mission is to solve
the riddle of this world.
If one of us survives,
we all survive.
[blows gently]
[Wade] There's someone behind everything.
You just have to dig.
[speaking inaudibly]
My Lord, we can help you.
[tense music building]
[Jin] I think they're real.
And they're coming.
[music swells]
[explosion blasts]
[somber closing theme playing]
[closing theme fades]