[ominous music playing]
[Pastor Ken] What did you hope
to get out of being here today?
I just wanna help people.
When you learn how to serve,
then you're welcome here anytime.
Perry Abbott is in violation of his bail,
therefore the deed to your ranch
shall be forfeited.
[groans]
[speaking Shoshone]
If something happens,
you might never get back to your time.
[Joy Hawk] I know someone named Royal,
tries to be a good man.
Men like your father,
where I come from,
they jail men like him.
[Levi Sumner]
Go on, Royal.
Know this, the day you die,
your family will rejoice.
[Joy gasps]
Royal!
Royal! Wait!
[intense dramatic music playing]
- Royal?
- Joy?
[dramatic music playing]
Joy?
[echoes faintly] Joy?
[normally] Joy!
[mumbles weakly]...doing by that hole?
What was that?
[mumbles indistinctly]
What were you doing in that hole?
Who shot you, Joy?
Joy, who shot you?
♪♪
You're bleeding somethin' awful.
Looks like it's gettin' infected.
I'm gonna take you to county.
Royal! [panting]
What were you doing in that hole?
My land, Sheriff.
What were you doing on it?
Joy, you're gonna be okay.
I'm gonna get you some water. Okay?
- Breathe.
- [tires squealing]
Breathe!
- [grunts sharply]
- I got it.
[gasping]
[groans, pants]
It's okay.
It's alright.
Goddamn it.
[eerie theme music playing]
[singers vocalizing]
[bell tolls]
- [auctioneer] Going once.
- [Cecilia Abbott] No.
[bell tolls]
[auctioneer] Going twice.
- [bell tolls]
- Sold.
[ominous music playing]
Testing, testing. One, two.
Is this thing on?
♪ Oh, don't you remember
a long time ago ♪
[door closes]
[glass shattering]
[men grunting]
[man laughs]
Grandmother's vase,
that's my grandmother's vase!
What are you doing?
Who knew all of this
would be worth so much?
[muffled, distorted]
No!
[auctioneer]
The Abbott ranch is sold
to Dawn Rivers for $500,000.
This is my place!
[cheering]
It's my place!
- [cheering continues]
- This is my place!
[groaning]
[grunting]
No!
This is my place! It's mine!
[young girl singing]
♪ Oh, don't you remember ♪
♪ A long time ago ♪
♪ Two poor little babes ♪
♪ Their names I don't know ♪
♪ And when it was night,
so sad was their plight ♪
♪ The sun went down
and the moon gave no light ♪
♪ And when they were dead ♪
♪ The robins so red
brought strawberry leaves ♪
[screeches]
- ♪ And over them spread ♪♪
- [bell tolls]
[Autumn] Cecilia?
[grunts]
You were screaming your lungs out.
- Hmm.
- I'll get you a glass of water.
No, no, no. I'm fine.
Wh-what were you dreaming about?
Did Royal call?
[Autumn] No.
Oh, God.
I don't know what to do.
When do you need to start packing?
[Cecilia groans]
[Cecilia] Oh, God.
[Autumn]
How much time do you have?
I don't know! I don't know!
Stop just a minute.
Okay.
Okay, I don't want...
I don't wanna pack.
I don't wanna...
I don't wanna sell the house.
I want my granddaughter back
and I want my son back!
That's what I want!
- Well, you need to move.
- I don't...
[mug shatters]
Shut up!
Please.
Be right back.
[clerk rapping] ♪ Then imagine lying dead
in the arms of your enemy ♪
♪ Imagine peace on this Earth
when there's no grief ♪
♪ Imagine grief on this Earth
when there's no peace ♪
♪ Yeah, I see the fear in your eyes ♪
♪ And hear your final breath ♪
♪ How much longer will it be
until it's all done? ♪
♪ Total darkness and ease be in all one ♪
♪ Oh, I'll be rolling to this beat ♪
♪ 'Cause there are none ♪
♪ Got my hand on the side... ♪♪
- [Royal Abbott] Hey.
- [pounds on table]
[rap song playing over earphones]
My bad.
[Royal clears throat]
How much?
[panting]
There you go.
Thank you.
[man] Oh, hey, Mr. Abbott.
Earl Chinlund's son, Jess.
Oh. Hey, Deputy.
How's your, uh, pa?
Yeah, he's good.
Arthritis and the like, but good.
- Well, you give him my best.
- [Jess] Yeah.
- Hey, Mr. Abbott?
- Yeah?
I'm sorry about all your troubles.
Perry. Granddaughter.
Yeah, I appreciate that.
[Jess]
All of Wabang's gone so topsy-turvy.
And the Sheriff's still missing.
Take care, Deputy.
One of your officers is outside.
Chinlund.
Another one behind the wheel.
[engine revs]
Oh! [exhales deeply]
[Royal] Drink this.
Nah, drink the whole thing.
Ah, damn it.
What?
They're following us.
[Joy] Don't speed.
How you feelin'?
[Joy huffing]
Shitty.
You want them to take you
the rest of the way?
[Joy] Mm-mmm.
Take me to the res.
To Wind River?
Don't they have checkpoints for outsiders?
Exactly.
Those two can't cross.
They're gonna have
a lot of questions for both of us.
I'm not ready to answer
anything right now.
[Cecilia sobbing]
[Cecilia wailing]
[Cecilia sighs]
You don't have to
go through this on your own.
[sniffles]
I've...
I've never felt this helpless in my life.
[sighs]
- Cecilia?
- Mm-hmm.
It doesn't make you any stronger
going through this alone.
Okay.
Come with me.
Dude's standing there, ass naked.
No joke, no chonies, nothing.
Talking about his time
walkin' with the elders.
He's here from 1972.
And you know that type of...
1972?
1982.
Damn it!
This is bad, isn't it?
No, no, it's good.
I mean, story's moving along.
I'm believing you.
Shit, it sucks, bro.
Oh, stranger danger.
Light 'em up.
[siren wails, chirps]
Sir, roll your windows down.
I got a wounded woman in here.
Edgar, it's your cousin, Joy.
Hands on the steering wheel.
- What?
- [Edgar] Now.
- [Joy] No, guys!
- Alright, alright.
Joy, what the fuck is going on?
He's taking me to IHS.
[sighs]
Why are your people here?
They looking for you?
Just hold 'em off, okay?
Dan, host our friends.
Got it.
Get back on the road.
IHS is a few more miles out.
Alright.
Autumn.
"Fear not for nothing is covered
that will not be revealed.
Nothing hidden
that will not be known."
Remember when the pastor said that?
If you're scared to go in there,
you need to rethink God.
Come on, Cecilia.
She's a woman in need,
the Abbots are in need.
Instead of putting it all on God,
why don't you take
some responsibility for yourself?
- You're responsible for that.
- Think of what you're saying.
And you're misleading people.
And they'll waste their entire lives
under this false deception
and delusion of faith.
[Pastor Ken]
Autumn! What are you doing?
- Cecilia...
- [Autumn] She needs $500,000
or she's gonna lose her ranch.
She's gonna lose it forever.
Cecilia, is that true?
Mm-hmm.
[Pastor Ken]
Oh, Cecilia.
So find the money. Help her out.
We don't have $500,000.
This church does not have $500,000.
This is a simple church.
This is a town full of old money.
- My congregation would do anything...
- Are they exempt from doing God's work?
...to help Cecilia,
but we do not have that.
Autumn, why didn't you tell me
this is what you were gonna do?
Because I knew
that you wouldn't come with me if...
You're asking the people
of this church for money,
money they don't have,
while your family is rich.
Why?
Because I want you to see
what these people are really like,
who they actually are.
Well, be the example
you want them to be.
Call. Ask your family for money.
Amen to that.
[beeps]
- [automated response] We're sorry.
- [sighs]
You have reached a number
that has been disconnected
or is no longer in service.
That's weird. I...
I think my sister
will know where she is.
[line rings]
[beeps]
[automated response]
We're sorry.
You have reached a number
that has been disconnected
or is no longer in service.
Beware of false prophets
kicking and screaming for miracles
while you're unknowingly being rebuked
for your vanity,
'cause I see you
for who you really are,
and that's a dime-store philosopher,
sanctimonious huckster
with nothing worth buying.
And I bet your family
abandoned you a long time ago.
Pastor, you're taking the high road?
- That's not Christlike.
- [Pastor Ken] Cecilia, spare yourself.
Not all people can be saved.
Well, how do you know if you don't try?
Today she tried.
Cecilia.
You alright?
Yeah.
You're somethin' else.
What do you mean?
When you believe in something,
nothing's gonna change your mind.
Yeah, that's just who I am.
Well, it's who I am too.
But I had forgotten.
You just reminded me.
Thank you.
I thought you would've been mad.
I am. No, I am.
Well...
You know, there's only one person I know
who can get that angry.
- Who?
- Amy.
I'm so worried
that I've missed who I am.
I've just been blind to so many things.
We all are.
Yeah, we all are.
[sighs]
First time at IHS?
Sure.
Can I ask you a question?
You just did.
Where'd you find Joy again?
[sighs]
What's your real question?
The one I just asked.
You know, let's say I did
something bad to your cousin,
would it make a lot of sense
that I would bring her here after?
- Good point.
- [Royal] Hmm.
Domestics do it all the time.
She was shot when you found her?
- She was.
- [Edgar] Hmm.
And, uh, you just did
the neighborly thing?
Again, get to what you're asking.
Did you put your fuckin' hands
on my family?
[sighs]
Only to get her here.
[Levi]
Go on, Royal.
Sight down like I taught you.
Look, I'm not trying to be an asshole.
Just don't think
you're gonna believe anything I tell you.
[Royal grunts softly]
[Edgar] You alright?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm alright.
Alright.
Uh, I'm gonna go check on Joy.
Hey.
I'm Deputy Jess Chinlund.
Amelia County Sheriff's Department.
What do you want, Deputy Jess Chinlund?
[Jess] What's your name?
Daniel.
Look, Dan, uh...
I got this feeling that I can't shake
that our boss is, uh,
in your jurisdiction right now.
And?
And I really need to know if she's okay.
Well, Deputy Sheriff...
you're just gonna
have to wait in your car.
I just wanna make sure she's okay.
[nurse] Joy's awake.
She wants to see you.
You sure about that now?
She said the white guy.
Thank you.
Still feelin' shitty?
Kinda.
[Royal] Hmm.
Thank you again.
[sighs]
You wanna start or should I?
What are we startin'?
Fine.
I ended up in your West Pasture
'cause I time traveled through that hole.
Figured I'd cut through
all the bullshit.
Mm-hmm.
That's not a question.
[Joy scoffs]
[Joy] Right.
I lived in the 1880s for four years.
Met Shoshone,
hunted with them, made friends...
was accepted by them.
While I was there,
I met a boy named Royal...
who saved my life.
[rifle cocks]
And I'm bettin' he was you.
What makes you think that?
I just told you I traveled through time
and you didn't even flinch.
Not a goddamn word.
That boy shot his father...
[gunshot]
to save me.
- To save you?
- [Joy] Yeah.
[gunshot]
And he had every right not to.
They were huntin' me
and another native girl.
[Joy gasps]
I always believed that I shot my father
in a hunting accident.
Ran and jumped in that hole...
thinkin' I'd disappear.
Not how it happened when I was there.
- You were there for four years?
- [Joy] Mm-hmm.
Years?
You were only missing
for a few days, that's all.
A-a few days?
You know, we have stories.
Old... old stories.
Um...
What do you think it is?
The hole?
I don't know.
There were so many signs that...
came before all this happened.
Like what?
Harlan talking about
dinosaurs in caves.
A guy I arrested told me
about people disappearing.
That mountain that just
vanished and reappeared.
[Royal, softly] Hmm.
You have someone you can talk to?
Talk to?
It's gonna eat you up
to keep this all inside.
I got Martha.
Good.
'Cause I spent
the last 50 years lying...
to the world.
I told you my family
can't know about any of this.
To my family.
There's a lot I can't explain.
- Well, try!
- I am trying.
First lie is the hardest...
then it just gets easier.
My family's broken now because of it.
Tell the truth...
before it's too late.
[Joy]
I have a feeling you and I
are gonna be havin'
more of these conversations, Royal.
Get some rest.
♪ Till we meet again ♪
♪ Just say when ♪
I'm Roy... Royal.
I'm Ceci Abbott.
Royal? Royal?
[Jess]
Mr. Abbott?
Deputy.
Why'd you run?
I just drove where she told me to drive.
Earl raised you well.
I'll be seeing you, Mr. Abbott.
Yeah, I heard that enough
to know it's true.
♪ To see you leave ♪
♪ And here we go
beginning at the end ♪♪
Where are we? What is this place?
Somethin' I gotta make right.
Autumn, do not leave this car
no matter what.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Lewis?
It's Cecilia Abbott.
- The fuck you want? Get down now.
- [Cecilia] Oh. Oh.
[Lewis] Now.
Autumn, stay there.
What are you doing back here?
Could you, could you
put the gun down, please?
Please?
You came to my sweat and threatened me
with a shotgun, I'm good here.
If you hurt her, I'll...
[Lewis] You'll what?
Who's got the gun here?
Don't move.
Tell blondie to chill out.
- [Cecilia] Autumn, I-I got this.
- [Lewis] Fuckin' chill out.
I can, I can handle this, Autumn.
What are you even doing here?
I came to apologize for the shotgun,
for taking my anger out on you.
I told you not to move!
I'll blow her brains out right now!
Listen, Lewis, I just wanna
tell you that I'm sorry.
That's why I'm here.
I wanna push past my, my pain
over my granddaughter, alright?
Just 'cause I'm in pain that doesn't mean
I can, I can cause other people pain.
That's not right, and I'm sorry.
[inhales deeply] Motherfucker.
[line ringing]
[Rebecca] [on phone]:
Hello?
Yeah, it's me.
[Rebecca]
Cecilia?
Yeah, she's here again.
[Rebecca Abbott]
Are you serious?
Yeah. Alright, listen.
[Rebecca sighs]
Put the kid on the phone.
[Rebecca]
No.
Put Amy on the phone, Rebecca.
I'm tired of this shit.
[Rebecca]
Oh... fuck. Okay.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hello?
[Rebecca]
You have one minute.
Amy, it's your grandmother.
Amy, how are you?
[Amy Abbott]
Why'd you lie to me?
My mom told me what you said to her.
You ran her off.
Oh, Amy, Amy, I can, I can explain.
[Amy]
I don't wanna talk to you.
[disconnects call]
Amy? Amy?
[melancholy music playing]
[sighs]
Don't come back here again.
[Cecilia groans]
Two of 'em smelled like ammonia.
Probably meth'd out.
Had no idea they snatched the sheriff.
Real masterminds, huh?
All because I wanted some gum
and went to the wrong liquor store.
They thought they were
gonna be quick in and out and
everyone got in over their heads,
including me.
Any idea where they took you?
Not sure where exactly.
They knocked me out, threw me in a trunk.
Ended up in a cabin.
Maybe... a few minutes or hours.
Time gets funny that way.
Yeah.
Well, you're back.
That's all that matters.
Happy to be back.
Um, I figure first thing we'll do
is put you with Betsy.
Well, maybe she can sketch their faces,
put out a BOLO.
Feds may wanna chat too.
I don't think we'll find 'em.
Well, maybe, maybe not.
They can't get away with it.
They won't.
Entire department's ready
to get after this.
Shit, Matt's been shook.
Think he was ready to ask
for a federal taskforce or something...
Jess, I just wanna move forward.
You, uh, you talk to your wife yet?
No.
They smashed my phone.
Mind if I use yours?
There you go.
I'll, uh, let you have some privacy.
You know, you seem different.
Your hair or something's...
I won't be long.
Okay.
[line ringing]
[Martha Hawk]
Hello?
Martha?
Joy?
It's me, baby.
- [Martha] Baby.
- Yeah.
[Martha]
Where are you?
[cow moos]
[Cecilia]
Is that Luke Tillerson?
Oh, I'm not up for his bull crap today.
[Autumn]
I think he's here to see me.
[Cecilia]
Is that so?
[Autumn]
It's complicated.
Just make sure he's outta here
before Royal gets home.
Won't be long.
[Luke] Oh.
What are you doing here?
[Luke]
I brought you... somethin'.
What's the matter with you, Luke?
[Luke] Oh.
I... I found some of that mineral...
in Billy's room.
[sighs] I wanted to
keep it all... for myself.
But I thought you deserved to see.
See what?
[Luke] Yourself.
You swallow it.
And when you're done...
tell me what you see.
Okay?
[engine starts]
[gentle music playing]
[door opens]
Hi.
[Royal] Hey.
You came back.
It's my home.
I'm sorry about what I said
about you being an Abbott.
Hmm.
You needed to say it...
and I needed to hear it.
It's back...
and I need for you to see it yourself.
Okay.
[horse whinnies]
[somber music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[pants]
[groans]
[young girl singing]
♪ Oh, don't you remember ♪
♪ A long time ago ♪
♪ Two poor little babes ♪
♪ Their names I don't know ♪♪
[dramatic music playing]
I had just come out of the hole
when you and Casey found me.
[scoffs] If you hadn't
have been there, I...
I don't know what would've happened.
How did you spend all those years
without talking to anybody?
Well, I didn't talk to you but...
you were right there by my side.
I don't want that to change.
It won't.
[♪ Beck: "Nobody's Fault But My Own"]
[bright guitar music playing]
♪ Treated you like a rusty blade ♪
♪ A throwaway from an open grave ♪
♪ Cut you loose
from a chain gang and let you go ♪
♪ And on the day you said it's true ♪
♪ Some love holds, some gets used ♪
♪ Tried to tell you I never knew
it could be so sweet ♪
♪ Who could ever be so cruel? ♪
♪ Blame the devil
for the things you do ♪
♪ It's such a selfish way to lose ♪
♪ The way you lose
these wasted blues ♪
♪ These wasted blues ♪
♪ Tell me that it's nobody's fault ♪
♪ Nobody's fault but my own ♪
♪ Nobody's fault ♪
♪ But my own ♪♪