[8-bit video game music]
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
[coin clatters]
[trills]
[ticking]
[coffee machine bubbling]
[door opens, hinge creaking]
["Foreplay/Long Time" by Boston]
[phone vibrating]
[screams]
ROY NARRATING:
Wakey-wakey! Heads-up.
- [man grunts]
- Shoes. Pants.
Low bridge! Shirt.
On your left. I'll take that.
[machete clatters]
Block. Slap.
Knife switch.
Rip him. Flip him.
OK. Coffee, anyone?
Can you imagine
waking up every day
with some random asshole
like Mr Good Morning here
trying to hack you up
with a fucking machete?
Seriously.
Arggh!
This might have been fun
for a while.
You're fucking dead!
Once the shock wore off,
once I realised
what the hell was happening,
after nearly 140 times,
it just fucking got annoying
and I want it to stop.
- [whirring]
- But I know it won't.
You know how people say,
"Oh, I can do that
with my eyes closed,"
and you always think
they sound like assholes?
But... whatever.
Watch.
[grunts]
[screams]
Sorry, pal!
They think you're me!
[gunfire]
As many times as I've seen this
happen to my apartment,
I still can't help but think,
"Fuck! Man, this is a lease."
The landlord is already
an asshole anyway
and I'm never, ever getting
my security deposit back.
[bullets ricochet and echo]
It wasn't always like this.
I was happy once. I really was.
I had a woman
that I loved, but...
..now I'm just pissed off.
[helicopter whirring echoes]
Ugh!
[watch beeping]
Ah, shit. Gotta jump.
["Foreplay/Long Time" continues]
Arggh!
- [thud]
- Ow!
[grunts]
I missed this truck
exactly 22 times before.
You know how it feels
falling four storeys
to the street below?
[screams]
It fucking hurts
is how it feels.
[horns honking]
Mr Man's-Man
in the Challenger here
screams at date-rape volume
every single time.
- [shrilly] I'm being carjacked!
- "I'm being carjacked!"
Yes, you are.
The next set of assholes trying
to kill me are in that minivan.
Could you get through
this traffic, please?
- Don't tell me how to drive.
- I'm not telling you...
Esmerelda the chauffeur and Pam.
You love to argue.
I have no fucking idea
if those are
their real names
because I never stop
to say hello.
[engine revs]
[silenced gunshots]
[rock music continues]
[horn blares]
Now, after the bus, it's pretty
much smooth sailing and I can...
Wait a second. Did I...
Oh, shit.
- Did I get to the bus yet?
- [horn honks]
- [people screaming]
- Nope.
MAN: Oh, sweet Jesus!
God?
- [siren blaring]
- Don't feel bad for me.
This kinda shit
happens every day.
I used to complain
that every day felt the same
and then May 9th came,
and now every day IS the same.
[screams]
Ugh, same wake-up scream,
same machete-wielding asshole,
same everything,
with slight variations.
- [thud]
- Ohh!
Mother... Ugh!
[helicopter approaching]
Oh...
One thing that never changes...
..is I die
every single day.
I die.
Here's a little highlight reel.
- [cheerful jazzy music]
- Arggh!
Now, truth be told,
I don't even know why
they want to kill me,
or what I've done
to deserve getting killed,
but there's a shit-ton of 'em.
- You've met Pam.
- [horn honking tunefully]
[staccato gunshots]
She did that to me 14 times
before I finally got
her timing down.
This little angel-faced asshole
is known as Guan Yin.
[blade slices]
How do I know her name?
I am Guan Yin.
And Guan Yin has done this.
Her name means
"Goddess of Mercy".
I think she digs irony.
I call this little
cocky motherfucker Kaboom.
- [beeping]
- What's up, pretty boy?
You fucking weirdo dwarf.
What are you doing?
- Oh, I don't like that attitude.
- [device whirring]
I've given them all nicknames -
Pam, Smiley, the German Twins,
Roy Number Two,
who happens to be
some asshole who looks
exactly like me.
[people scream]
Now, sometimes
I manage to kill them.
[bodies thud]
But it doesn't matter.
They always find me
and eventually they take me out.
I am Guan Yin.
And Guan Yin has done this.
I don't know
how this is possible
or why I keep
repeating the same day.
I've never had time
to figure it out.
It's a shit show
from the second I open my eyes.
Jemma, the only woman
I've ever loved
and the one person who has
the answers I'm looking for.
[line ringing]
[phone trills]
Hello.
Uh, I'm looking
for Dr Jemma Wells.
Who's this?
This is her hus...
Um, her boyfriend Roy.
Ah, Captain Roy Pulver,
he of Delta Force fame.
Who's this?
This is Colonel Clive Ventor.
- Jemma's boss.
- Until recently.
Is she around?
Well, no, unfortunately
she's not.
Oh, do you know
when she'll be back?
Now, that is more of
a cosmic question
that I'd have to hand over
to a higher power.
Huh?
She's dead.
What?
VENTOR: Hate to be the bearer
of bad news,
but Miss Wells
took a nasty spill
and snapped her neck last night.
An accident in the lab,
working late,
likely very fatigued.
- No.
- [car boot shuts]
Can I ask where you are?
- Eins...
- Zwei...
ROY: That was
no fucking accident.
BOTH: Drei!
Why is she dead? Who killed her?
I have never lived
long enough to find out.
OK, so where were we?
Oh, yeah, the bus.
Fuck!
[tyres squeal]
[gunfire]
[speaking Spanish]
Oh, honey, we got
ourselves a cowboy.
I think I'm gonna have
to get serious here.
The fuck?
Fuck me!
Oh! Fuck!
[car alarm blaring]
Nah, I think they deserved it.
[cheerful Chinese
pop music plays]
[doorbell chimes]
MAN: Hey, Roy!
Hey, Jake.
Whoa. You look like
death taking a dump.
- What happened to you?
- I just woke up wrong.
- I'm fine, Jake.
- Alright.
Happens all the time.
Can I get a large bottle
of that baijiu, please?
You know what, Jake?
- Make it two large bottles.
- Two! Jesus Christ.
Hear ye, hear ye,
Sir Osis of Liver!
[laughing] I'm just kidding.
Alcoholics Unanimous,
am I right?
You only got today, right, Jake?
'Cause tomorrow
isn't guaranteed.
Fuckin'-A, pal. Fuckin'-A.
This kid is all about
the shutdown.
How can you drink like that?
Ohh!
How can you not?
You know, a lot of expert
internal security pundits -
and, mind you, I'm one of them -
think that the next 9/11 will
target our distilled spirits.
Now, you have got a country
with a rate of alcoholism
and binge drinking somewhere
in the 38th percentile,
so should you wipe out
en masse...
ROY: This douchebag's
named Dave.
Dave is a security specialist
for some private firm
and it doesn't matter
what my answer is
to him asking,
"How can you drink like that?"
he always launches into
this exact same fucking speech.
I know what he's gonna say
word for word.
I know everything
that's gonna happen
from the second I walk in.
[doorbell chimes]
At 11:05, this famous
Chinese swordfighter comes in.
She was a 12-time
world champion.
Holy shit! Dai Feng.
Roy, you know she's
one of the most famous...
ROY: Wudang Chinese
sword masters?
- JAKE: 12-time...
- World champion.
- Have I told you about her?
- A hundred times.
- Really? I don't remember.
- I do.
Pedro, clear a table
for Sifu Feng.
Hi. Please sit.
ROY: Sifu Feng here is the
reason I have to bust my ass
to get to the bar every day.
If I get here
any later than 11:00,
she takes the last seat
at the bar.
[country rock music plays]
JAKE: Oh, shit.
She just stared at me.
Have you ever been with a woman?
Excuse me?
Think I'm catching a fish,
if you know what I mean.
I think you have a better chance
of growing a penis
on your forehead, Jake.
[bell dings]
At around noon...
OK, I... I feel a little bit bad
about this next thing.
I just love seeing him wipe out.
I'm sorry. I know
I should probably warn him.
But it's just so fucking funny
and it's not like I got a lot
to laugh about these days.
You can't file
workman's comp, Pedro!
No-one will believe you!
At 12:20, Dave the pantload
finally goes back to work.
You better hope
the terrorists don't decide
to start poisoning
the world's baijiu supply, Roy!
But not before delivering
that little gut-buster.
[Dave laughs,
speaks indistinctly]
- Too much.
- ROY: Sit down, Dave.
Excuse me?
I wanna tell you a story.
Whoa! OK, I'm bombed today.
Little twist on the war story.
I start talking about
the other times I've died
when I've had too much to drink.
You ever been shot
in the face, Dave?
Huh?
I was shot in the face.
And a funny thing happened
to me right before I died.
This was a while back now.
I think it was a .45 ACP round.
Enters here, clean.
Bullet winds up
in my mouth, almost intact,
and I remember tasting steak.
Yeah, like a really,
really good rib eye.
Mmm!
And it wasn't only
until much later
when I was alive again
I said, "Shit...
"That was my tongue being cooked
by the heat of the bullet."
That's what I tasted, my tongue.
You believe that shit?
That's fucking wild.
That is a true story, Dave.
[Dave and Jake
chuckle awkwardly]
Good stuff, buddy.
Ever thought about getting
a sober coach?
Copy that.
[bell dings]
ROY: At exactly 12:47...
Let me get to that in a second.
But say a quarter till,
I've usually got
a really, really good buzz
and I'm feeling fucking good.
You see, as long as
I make it to this bar,
I can drink until they find me.
[sighs]
I can get absolutely
shit-faced...
..and not feel a thing.
- [doorbell chimes]
- [people exclaim]
12:47 pm.
I've never, not once,
made it a minute
past this point.
Why do I let it happen?
Why not?
'Cause outside of this bar,
no matter what direction I run
and no matter how hard I fight,
I have never lived
past 12:47 pm.
They always get me.
[guns cocking]
Bunch of assholes I've never met
killing me for reasons
that remain a mystery.
And she's dead, my girl.
Gone in a moment further back
than I can ever go,
stuck here in the death loop
of a never-ending day.
I know I can't keep
drinking my way through it...
..not when every day
ends like this.
I need a plan now.
I need to make somebody pay.
They have an army.
All I have is time.
Yesterday was months ago.
[muzak plays]
[elevator bell dings]
Great.
Yep, that's good.
[clears throat]
Guys, um, can you give me
a second, please?
WOMAN: Sure.
My God, woman.
Look at you.
- Hi.
- Hey.
[chuckles]
So have you developed
some allergic reaction
to the phones?
No, no, I just got back.
My cell phone was shut off,
and I didn't get a chance to
square away my landline, so...
- So they shut that off too?
- Eh, yeah.
I mean, it's really just luck
that you got in touch
with me at all.
Oh, yeah! Luck, yeah.
The amount of luck it took
to find you in the bar
at the bottom
of your apartment building.
What were the odds?
[Roy chuckles]
Well, hello there, sarcasm.
How you been, stranger?
Haven't heard
from you in a while.
- [paper rustles]
- What's that?
ROY: I brought a résumé.
But the printer I used
was kind of low on ink
so the Delta Force section
is hard to read.
Shh.
- Is that gonna hurt my chances?
- Ehh.
- Come here.
- Hmm?
They, uh, wear uniforms here.
- Security, so...
- Oh, very cool, yeah.
- So I need to just...
- I mean, it's not those...
Whoa!
Those maroon things,
like mall security?
'Cause I can't rock that look.
Maroon? Like... my dress?
No, not like your dress
because that would be sexy.
- No, I'm just saying.
- Fine.
Anyway, I...
What's the salary here anyway?
ROY ON SPEAKERS: Have any idea?
And is there a medical copay?
Because I have a pre-existing,
you know, with the combat stuff.
Hey, what do you do here?
It looks really... big.
Been working on it a while?
JEMMA: Just long enough, I hope.
ROY: What is that thing anyway?
That's five years' worth
of sleepless nights
and round-the-clock research.
And it means more to me
than you can possibly imagine.
What does it do?
- What's it do?
- Mm.
Unmakes all of time and space...
..and destroys the planet in its
entirety, if improperly used.
ROY: No shit.
Wait. Like, doomsday destroy?
Well, you must
be really stressed!
JEMMA: Mm-hm.
Wow. Look at Joe.
Jesus, he's getting
so big, Jemma.
Hey, you mind
if I swap this out?
- Huh?
- This... this picture.
You got another one of these?
Oh, yeah, sure, you can take it.
What's your weight?
Uh...
I'm doing... I'm doing a special
paleo thing, so it's, like, 175.
Still drinking?
- Yeah.
- I'll put 180.
180.
Have you thought
about telling him?
It would mean a lot to me
if we could tell him, Jemma.
[scoffs] Honestly,
what would he gain?
You've been absent
most of his life.
Why do you gotta
say it like that,
like it wouldn't be worth it
if I got to know him now,
you know?
My work took me away
from you guys.
- Your work?
- Yeah.
Your work?
You loved that life a lot more
than you loved the idea
of sharing one with us.
Getting shot at
is way more exciting
than diapers and minivans.
Right, right, right, there's
your go-to argument,
and you know that.
I'm just an asshole who didn't
wanna stick around, right?
What does it matter
anymore, Roy?
I mean, we've both moved on,
we've made our decision,
and Joe adores you anyway.
- He adores me?
- Yeah.
Well, what'd he say about me?
What do you want, Roy?
I lost you, OK?
I know that I blew it.
I made my peace with it.
Please don't let
that happen with my son.
That's all I'm asking.
He's our boy, Jemma.
[door opens]
- MAN: Dr Wells.
- Just a minute.
Oh, sorry, Brett.
Uh, this is Roy. Roy, Brett.
Brett's head of security
here at Dynow.
Your office is in
a restricted area, Dr Wells,
and is therefore off-limits.
I made it clear to the colonel
that I would accept visitors
when I deemed it appropriate.
I was just dropping off
my résumé, big guy.
It's all good.
Well, we're not hiring
right now, Captain Pulver.
Tell him I'll be there
in a moment.
The colonel's waiting.
What a dick.
I thought you said
you were hiring.
They are. We are.
I am.
What are you talking about?
It's a very specific
security detail.
Black bag stuff, like, covert?
Beyond.
Really?
When do I start?
[lowly] Sooner than you think.
VENTOR: I read the man's résumé
and I see cause for concern.
He doesn't look like much.
Well, no-one ever notices
the housefly
till he fucks up
a good bowl of soup, Brett.
There's something
I don't like about him.
He has that... trait.
What trait is that?
The overachiever who makes up
for a lack of talent
with hustle.
The guy in the playground
I grew up hating.
Vet his service history.
If it's accurate, I want him
tracked and monitored.
If he becomes problematic,
we'll deal with him.
And, uh, reach outside
the normal ranks -
no-one that could
connect back to us.
The more random
the assets, the better.
Find some real freaks.
OK, I'm gonna get out of here,
grab a little vino,
maybe some...
- Just let me fix your hair.
- Ow, ow, Jemma!
I'm bleeding.
Did you get
my birthday present, Roy?
What are you doing here?
- You're acting so weird.
- Did you get it, the present?
- I sent it to you.
- I don't know.
- I haven't checked.
- Well, please do.
I sent it a few days ago.
I will. Of course I will.
VENTOR ON SPEAKERS: Dr Wells,
could I see you for a moment?
ROY: I'm going
to the hospital first.
JEMMA: Be there
in a moment, Colonel.
You drew blood.
Listen to me now, Roy.
OK, look, I know we haven't
seen much of each other lately,
and I know we've gone down
very different paths.
I know, but when I was...
It's important you listen!
Just listen!
Alright, you talk,
you talk, you talk.
OK. I've forgotten
how trying this can be.
OK. Now, I see a lot
of you in Joe. I do.
His determination,
his willingness to succeed
no matter what.
He has some of
your best qualities.
He does.
But he also has your selfishness
and your ability to just
disappear when it suits...
Just when I thought
we were turning a corner.
- ..and run from responsibility.
- OK, alright.
What do you want from me?
Just tell me, just tell me.
I want the man I fell
in love with a long time ago,
the one who gave me a son,
the strong, confident
version of you,
not the Roy who's out
every night getting hammered
and banging a different bimbo.
[door opens]
[whispers]
Remember this - Osiris.
- Osiris.
- OK.
[door opens, closes]
Whoa.
Look. It's Roid and Rage.
You know, carbohydrates
are not your friend, fellas.
[low ominous music]
VENTOR: Dr Wells, are you well?
Yes.
VENTOR:
Does cigar smoke bother you?
No, not at all.
The Spindle.
Well, we're experiencing
a minor delay at the moment.
Define 'minor'.
A week, two weeks at the most.
And why?
R&D is never an exact science.
And yet that's exactly what
we're after - exact science.
Your, uh, friend,
Captain Pulver.
JEMMA: Yes,
he dropped off a résumé.
And whatever possessed him?
Well, I may have mentioned,
in passing,
the military presence
here at the lab.
And whatever possessed you?
The security protocols
of this facility
should not be
the subject of pillow talk.
I can assure you they're not.
Roy and I are not in...
You are the mother
of his child, no?
[Ventor laughs] Huh.
Please, please, sit down.
Make yourself comfortable.
I don't want this to seem
like an interrogation.
I'm not one for long stories.
I'm someone who's always
appreciated brevity in any form.
The shorter, the better.
However, I do have one story
that I've told and retold,
and it's a story that I would
like to share with you now,
if you'll indulge me.
Oh. I happen to like
long stories.
Well, good.
Then we're both in luck.
So, Burma 1979.
I was doing skunk work
for the CIA,
smuggling enough opium
into the country
to backstop
a very bloody military coup
that we would eventually
stage a decade later.
This is all
mostly declassified, mostly.
At any rate, I find myself
in the jungle outside Rangoon,
sniping soldiers
from the KNU Liberation Front
in a three-day running firefight
that had cost me my entire team.
So there I am,
on the verge of being overrun
by a bunch of
machete-wielding rebels
who have terrible attitudes
and even worse hygiene,
and all I have is a Remington
Buckmaster with a shot-out scope
and 36 sleepless hours
in which to squeeze out a win.
Huh!
And then I hear it.
This piercing squeal,
like a steam whistle.
A wild boar.
Make you piss your pants.
The sound alone was enough
to make the rebels scatter.
No-one wants to
fuck with the tusks.
So now this son of a bitch
gets a sniff of me
and comes at me straightaway.
Now, I'd rather put a bullet
in 10 men than kill an animal,
but before I'm even presented
with the do-or-die of it all,
an 18-foot Burmese python
comes down from a banyan tree
and wraps up this raging hog
like a Christmas ham.
Huh! I've never seen
anything like it.
And for the next few hours,
I watch in wonder
as this snake slowly suffocates
and devours this pig.
It was oddly quiet
so I could hear everything,
the boar's bones snapping,
the bellows-like wheeze
as its lungs collapsed
that made it sound like
the snake was laughing.
[chuckles]
It remains the most
awe-inspiring
act of violence
I have ever seen.
But what struck me most,
even as the python
extended its jaws
a full two feet
to devour its prey...
..was the calm
and calculation in its eyes.
And it wasn't till later
when it finally moved
its midsection,
now distended with
the outline of that boar,
that I saw a dozen eggs.
Python eggs.
That boar was about
to trample its nest.
So what I had first perceived
as an act of aggression
was actually an act of love.
The snake killing the boar
not out of malice,
but out of necessity
to prevent its future
from being obliterated.
Hmm.
I enjoyed that story.
Oh, and I enjoy telling it.
I also thought it apt.
How so?
No more visitors to the lab.
No ex-boyfriends, old flames,
or shadowy figures
from the past.
If there's a delay in the work,
I want to be apprised
of it posthaste, yes?
Of course.
Thank you, Doctor.
That's wonderful.
VENTOR: Do watch your step.
[upbeat funky music]
- [laughter]
- ROY: You want another one?
WOMAN: Mm, another one of what?
Hey?
[laughing]
[woman purrs]
[Roy laughs] You are sweet.
[laughter continues]
So how long have you two
known each other?
Oh, we only met today.
He is my newest best friend.
Yes, I am.
Alice is a dental hygienist.
Which is weird
'cause I totally hate teeth.
I mean, just the texture of them
grosses me out.
Then a career
in dentistry seems...
Like the last thing
I should be doing?
Yeah, I know, I know.
But, you know, I'm...
I'm all about a challenge.
I like to, like, push myself
out of my comfort zone.
It's the only way
to grow, really.
ALICE: So true.
So pretty. Isn't he pretty?
- [Roy chuckles]
- ALICE: Mmm.
How long have you guys
known each other?
ROY: Oh, Gabrielle?
For as long as I've been
drinking in this bar.
Since he got back from overseas.
ALICE: Oh, danger! Do tell.
Oh, ladies, there's really
almost nothing to tell.
Then tell us almost nothing.
ALICE: Mm! But can you wait?
'Cause... I gotta pee.
Oh, my God. Hold that.
I'll be right back.
[Alice giggles]
You should take her home, Roy.
[laughs]
You should take her home.
[Roy chuckles]
You're about to ask,
"Why not take you home too,
Gabrielle?"
And I'll say...
.. "Maybe another night."
[Roy sighs]
I'm starting to wear you down.
[speaking French]
We'd have fun, Roy,
but we'll never be in love.
ROY: Oh, love!
- No.
- Why?
- Yeah.
Because you're still in love...
..with someone else.
It's in your eyes.
In the sadness I see there.
There is a woman you long for,
but it's not me.
And it's not
our lovely hygienist.
[phone ringing]
Bar, hello. Yeah.
It's for you.
ROY: Who the hell's
calling me now?
GABRIELLE: I don't know.
ROY: Hello?
Roy, can you hear me?
Jemma? What...
Are you still at the lab?
It's almost 3 am.
Jemma, you OK?
- You alright?
- Yeah, I'm fine, but...
What's going on? Listen...
Yeah, listen to me.
I think I might have
to do something drastic,
and if anything happens,
promise me
you'll do what you do...
[static, voice cutting out]
I can't... I can't hear you.
JEMMA: I'm gonna need your help.
ROY: Wait, wait.
What's going on? Are you OK?
JEMMA: I can't explain
it right now.
But you wouldn't
understand anyway.
[line beeping]
Hey, I think I lost you.
Jemma, call me back, OK?
Who was that?
It was my ex and she was...
She sounded pretty worked up.
[door opens and shuts]
It seems our dear doctor
has gone rogue.
Find her.
What did I miss?
ROY: Oh, hi.
Well, you know,
we were talking about
the hottest people
on the planet.
- Naturally, your name came up.
- Oh!
♪ Alcohol, oh, alcohol
♪ Got to put you down
♪ Tried to put you down now
♪ Tried to let you go
♪ Bled to death on alcohol
♪ I don't want you no more
♪ We don't want you no more now
♪ We don't want you no more... ♪
ROY: I should've tried
to call Jemma back,
but I was drunk and horny
and I didn't give a shit.
I didn't know
how important it was.
it would be the last time
that I'd ever hear her voice.
Some things you can't redo.
And some things you're forced
to do over and over again.
- [screams]
- [grunting]
I know this whole thing
leads back to her.
I just have no idea what
this whole thing actually is.
JEMMA: Did you get
my birthday present, Roy?
Did you get it, the present?
ROY: I don't know.
I haven't checked.
JEMMA: Well, please do.
I sent it a few days ago.
Remember this - Osiris.
ROY: "Happy birthday, Roy!
"May you always
live your life forward
"and always remember,
time waits for no man.
"XOX..."
- Ohh!
- [helicopter whirring]
Fuck me!
Let's do that again.
[grunting]
- [screams]
- [horn honks]
BOTH: I'm being carjacked!
[silenced gunshots]
[horn honks]
- [novelty horn toots]
- Fuck!
[people screaming]
Come on, come on. Let's go!
Dude, die already. Goddamn it.
WOMAN: He's in my way!
About fucking time.
- [screams]
- [grunting]
- I'm being...!
- Arggh!
[gunshots]
Don't read and drive, moron.
[novelty horn toots]
[engine revs]
Hah!
How did I never notice this?
[engine roars]
Shit. I missed the exit
to the Chinese restaurant
and the last time
I went anywhere else,
it ended up really bad.
I call this guy Smiley,
for obvious reasons.
[whistling thud]
At least getting shot is simple,
straightforward stuff.
SMILEY: Whoo-hoo!
Yeah, get some!
Who the hell thinks up
shit like this?
Whoo-hoo! Get some!
All I've been doing is running
from my life this entire time.
Now I've got my first real clue
to what the fuck
might be happening to me.
All I need now is a little
ceasefire and somewhere quiet
where I can get
some reading done.
"Osiris and Isis were
devoted husband and wife."
Blah, blah.
"She was an Egyptian
high priestess,
"ideal mother and wife,
"protector of the dead,
"skilled in all magical spells
"for transport through
the afterlife and beyond."
"Osiris was eventually
dismembered into 14 parts
"and scattered across Egypt
by his enemy."
What the fuck kind
of birthday present is this?
JEMMA: Happy birthday, Roy.
May you always
live your life forward.
And remember,
time waits for no man.
ROY: Joe.
What the hell's he doing?
- Shit.
- [video games blip and trill]
He doesn't know his mom is gone
and he's all alone now...
..that I'm the only family
he has left.
ROY: How you doing, pal?
$10 entry, brojam.
$5 per round,
double elimination.
What, uh... what do you got
going here?
Pop-up eSport tourney.
- What is that?
- Competitive video gaming.
We do mostly retro
'80s-based side-scrollers -
'Double Dragon', 'Altered
Beast', 'Street Fighter'.
We're purists, bro,
dedicated to video game's
golden age.
Analog or death.
8-bit is the shit.
How old are you?
The big 4-1.
[chuckles] Life creeps up.
- 41?
- Yeah.
You got a son here somewhere?
I'm childless by choice, bro.
[chuckles] Whose choice?
Keep it.
[games trilling]
[low ominous music]
Joe, yo! Hey.
Hey, bud.
Roy, hey. What's up?
Look at you!
You shot way up, huh?
I think you were, like,
maybe yea high
the last time I saw you.
- I didn't know you were a gamer.
- Oh, I am not a gamer.
Then what are you doing here?
Actually, I was gonna ask you
the same question, buddy.
Isn't it a school day?
I ditched.
Come on, buddy.
You can do better than this.
Well, I couldn't not come.
These are, like, my favourite
vintage video games,
and Mom would be really mad
if she knew I was here.
Mom would be really mad.
I'll tell you what.
I won't rat you out
if you tell me one thing.
OK.
What did you buy
from that boy upstairs,
the older boy?
I didn't buy anything.
Joe, I saw you.
- Oh!
- "Oh!"
JOE: It's an RPG card game.
I traded it with that kid.
You can be, like, all these
different assassins
and mercenaries and stuff.
- It's really cool.
- I bet it is.
So this is what
you got from him?
Mm-hm. What, did you think
I was buying drugs or something?
Or something.
I just turned 11.
I can't do that stuff.
[laughs] You can't do
that stuff ever, pal, OK?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Alright.
Let's go get some lunch.
We can come back, OK?
I wanna talk to you.
- OK.
- Alright?
The screen is broken anyway.
Oh, pfft. Piece of junk.
Come on.
- You hungry, bud?
- Yeah.
Yeah? What's your
favourite food?
- Pizza.
- Pizza?
- Mm-hm.
- We can get some pizza.
- What about sushi?
- I don't like sushi.
- You don't?
- No.
- How come?
- [girl exclaims]
- JOE: 'Cause it's sushi.
- Oh, that makes sense.
ROY: I have to tell him now,
tell him that his mother is
gone, tell him that... [sighs]
..he's never gonna see
her again, tell him that...
You know, Mom says
you're a bad-ass.
A bad-ass? She says that?
Well, she doesn't use that word,
but she says you're, like,
a SEAL team guy or something,
like, a soldier.
Mom talks about me?
Yeah, she mentions you a lot.
A lot?
Hey, are you like that guy,
the one from 'Taken',
who has a
"particular set of skills"?
- [laughs] Liam Neeson?
- Yeah.
No. He's kind of
a fake tough guy.
- But, yeah, I'm the real guy.
- Really?
I'm not kidding you. That's me.
Oh, that's so cool.
Hey, Joe.
[melancholy music]
I gotta tell you something, bud,
and it's gonna be
pretty hard to hear, OK?
I don't have
an easy way to say this.
ROY: 12:50.
Three minutes longer
than I've ever lived.
How?
The inside is all metal.
Then I went below ground.
They're tracking me.
[tense music]
JOE: What did you
wanna tell me, Roy?
[people scream]
[Roy grunts]
Joe...
..I'm your father.
In all that fear,
I saw my son's love for me
for a split second
and it was beautiful.
Please, please let this death
be the last.
- [woman screams]
- Motherfucker!
[grunts]
- How are you tracking me?
- Oh! Fuck you!
Fuck me? Where's the device?!
- Up your ass!
- Oh, you're full of ideas.
Ugh!
Fuck off.
OK, fuck off.
[grunts and yells]
[doorbell chimes]
JAKE: Hey, buddy!
OK. When you gotta go,
you gotta go.
Where's this tracker?
I know it's here.
Where is this thing?
Fuck...
Pedro, you wanna help me look?
And then I said,
"I will see your
counterintelligence expert
"and raise you
"a counter-surveillance
specialist, my friend."
You should have seen
the look on his face.
Dude, you're crazy!
- Dave.
- Hey, Roy.
Hey. Sorry to interrupt.
No, I was just telling Chef Jake
about this loudmouth...
Got it, great. Dave, you know
anything about tracking devices?
I don't know anything about
that kind of thing, Roy.
I know everything
about that kind of thing! Hah!
What are we talking?
Traditional transponder?
The kind you put on a person.
A body-based
or an implantable device?
What's better
if you don't want the person
to know they're being tracked?
Well, an implantable version
is loads more reliable.
A body-based device
would be attached to clothing...
Where do you implant it?
Where would you do it?
Most people think
subcutaneously,
just underneath the skin...
Dave, where would you put it?
- Oh, you mean me personally?
- You personally.
Ha-ha! A Dave special.
- What is that stupid face, Dave?
- Hm?
Yeah, yeah.
He gets it.
The teeth, Roy. The teeth!
Ideally, a molar.
You gotta be shitting me.
You look so handsome
with the mask on.
You have nothing to worry about.
Just keep breathing deeply.
It'll all be over soon.
[muffled voices]
So your mouth acts
as a natural transmitter.
- Dave?
- Yes?
Would you be able
to look at a tooth
and detect if there was
a tracking device in it?
I mean, not while it's
inside someone's mouth.
If that tooth were removed,
I could possibly check it out.
Jake, large bottle of baijiu
and a pair of pliers now.
[Roy screaming]
- No, no, no!
- [Roy groaning]
- [crack]
- Oh, goddamn this shit!
Don't worry, Dave.
It'll grow back.
Have you lost your mind?!
No, you need some damn help!
You're being so helpful.
What do you think?
- No.
- You sure?
- I'm positive!
- What time is it?
- Shit. It is 12:45.
- Oh, shit. We got two minutes.
No, it's time for you
to stop snatching
your damn teeth
out of your mouth!
- Are you crazy?
- [groans]
- Oh, fuck this shit!
- [screaming]
Oh, no, no, no! Oh, God!
- [Roy screams]
- [crack]
Shit! I should've stayed
my black ass home.
- Look!
- Oh, no! No!
Look!
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah? What?
Yeah, that tooth, mm-hm.
There's an irregularity
in that tooth.
- There is?
- Yeah.
Oh, my God. I would need
to see inside of it.
- Roy?
- Yeah.
- Carefully, OK?
- Careful.
- [crack]
No! No! That's not careful!
[panting]
Ohh!
You son of a bitch.
- Oh, my God. Roy?
- Uh-huh?
Someone paid a lot of money
to keep track of you.
- They did?
- Yeah.
A whole lot. I've never...
- [diner bell dings]
- I'll see you soon, Dave.
- [gunshot]
- ♪ Time has come today... ♪
[grunts]
♪ Young hearts
can go their way... ♪
Who did it?!
Who put the tracker in my mouth?
- Who did it?
- A guy called Brett.
ROY: Mr Frat Boy,
fake-baked, bald,
400-pound,
I-dye-my-beard-hair black
douchebag
head of Dynow security.
Alright.
I'm gonna punch a giant
fucking hole in his chest.
- JAKE: What's up, dog?
- Jake.
I need a large bottle of baijiu
and a pair of pliers now.
[groans]
♪ The rules
have changed today... ♪
ROY: I have died 144 times
as of today.
But this particular day,
I finally get to do
something about it.
♪ Time!
Time has come today
♪ Time! ♪
ROY: Drop it.
PAM: What, the tooth?
No, not the tooth.
I'm not dropping it.
Well, it drops or you drop.
This is a custom
handmade Walther PPK
that cost me nearly half
a million dollars at auction.
You bought a handgun
for half a million dollars?
And had my personal
pistolsmith fit it
with a vintage SD-22
SpielWaffen suppressor,
of which there are
six in the world,
for an additional $250,000.
750,000 bucks?
Correct.
Why in the fuck, Pam, would you
ever do something like that?
Pam?
Well, I never got your name
so I just call you Pam.
- We've met?
- Many, many times, in passing.
Let me see it.
Slow.
Hold it by the trigger guard.
Handle it as if
it were porcelain, please.
Soft as a whisper.
A.H.?
Adolf, Hitler.
Qué?
It was a personal gift
from Carl Walther.
Hitler kept it in his desk
in Munich.
You've been killing me
with fuckin' Hitler's gun
this whole time?
It was stolen by
an American serviceman in 1945.
- Jesus, what is wrong with you?
- Fast-forward to present day...
I didn't think this could
get any worse.
- ..a very pretty penny.
- And it has.
- Who sent you?
- Wouldn't you like to know.
- Hint, hint?
- Never.
Are you gonna kill me now?
No, Pam, I'm gonna shoot you.
[silenced gunshots]
That's for the Jews.
["Workin' For MCA"
by Lynyrd Skynyrd]
Those too.
[whistling thud]
[spits]
♪ Oh, seven years
of bad luck... ♪
Oh, get some! Come on, boy!
Get some!
ROY: Jemma put me here
on purpose.
I don't know how,
I don't know why.
But there's gotta
be a good reason.
Shit, there's gotta be
a great one.
- [ringtone plays]
- Look.
You lost your phone,
little fella.
But she's gone.
I can't get back
far enough to reach her,
so none of this matters now.
There's only one real piece
of business left.
[device whirrs]
- Revenge.
- [click]
[chuckles]
Things are getting warm now.
Did you eliminate the asset?
You mean assets, plural.
- Marshall?
- Hello, Brett.
Don't ask who this is 'cause
you know exactly who it is.
- Where's Marshall?
- Who's that, bomb boy?
The one I call Kaboom?
Well, he's at a big company
barbecue at the moment.
We're only missing two members -
you and the shithead
calling the shots.
You assume
there's someone above me.
You're a lapdog, pal,
so there's gotta be a leash.
I want who's holding it.
I want who killed Jemma.
I think it's Ventor.
Well, you know
where we are, hotshot.
Yeah, and I know
how to get there.
I'll see you in a minute,
motherfucker.
[engine revs]
I'm guessing the big boss man
has a penthouse view,
but I'm about sick to death
of all the sneaky, stealth,
behind-the-scenes bullshit.
Let's go old-school
and just kick the fucking
front door down.
[funk music]
[airbag deflates]
That was a good plan.
[groans weakly]
[gunshot]
I'm gonna gouge his eyes out.
[dramatic choral music]
[shouting and gunfire]
[grunts]
[beep]
Halt! Halt! Halt!
[device whirrs]
Fall back!
[guards yell]
I can do this all day, dick.
[gunshot]
[gate buzzes]
ROY: Hello, Roy Number Two.
- [tyres squeal]
- [distant gunshot]
Goodbye, Roy Number Two.
[gate buzzes]
GUARD: Go ahead.
Yeah, go ahead.
[detector beeps]
Roy Number Two was unarmed,
and I'm positive I'm not getting
a weapon past these guys.
[elevator bell dings]
Sir?
Oh, yeah, sorry.
Got the... card here.
Just gonna...
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Access denied.
Oh, that's, uh...
It must be me.
- [mutters]
- [buzzes]
- [grunting]
- [gunshot]
- [grunts]
- [engine revs]
- What's up?
- Access denied.
[gunshot]
- Hi, Roy.
- Ugh!
ROY: So do I do
a Butch and Sundance
blaze-of-glory bit here?
Nah.
Never say die.
That was weird.
- [grunts]
- [gunfire]
- [horns blare]
- [detector beeps]
- [groans]
- You big motherfucker!
[panting]
Oh, fuck.
Arggh!
[elevator bell dings]
GUAN YIN: Hello, handsome!
ROY: You cut my head off
a couple dozen times.
Someone's been
the busiest little beaver.
What are you gonna do with that?
I was thinking about
fucking you up.
You remember
in 'Raiders', that asshole
who was twirling
a sword around and around,
thinking he was
all cool and shit?
Indy just shot him 'cause
he was exhausted, impatient,
and just couldn't
take the bullshit anymore.
- You remember that?
- Yeah.
[click]
["Mean Little Mama"
by Roy Orbison]
- Fuck!
- Huh!
Arggh!
ROY: Something
you might not know
about getting killed
with a sword -
with the exception
of attempt number 15,
getting killed with a sword
hurts worse than a gunshot.
[shrieking]
Another lesser known fact
about swords.
[groans]
They hurt a hell of a lot more
coming out.
Fun fact.
Harrison Ford had the shits
and that's why he shot that guy.
["Mean Little Mama" continues]
I am Guan Yin.
And Guan Yin has done this.
[song continues]
- Hyah!
- Ooh!
I am Guan Yin.
And Guan Yin has done this.
[body thuds]
I am Guan Yin.
And Guan Yin has done this.
[Roy mumbles]
I'm Guan Yin
and I have done this.
ROY: And this
isn't even the worst part.
This is.
Ventor.
The man who killed Jemma.
The same bozo that's had me
killed 150 fucking times.
Captain,
as first impressions go,
this is truly stand-out stuff.
How you were able to dispatch
the elite level
of high-speed professionals
we threw at you
is really remarkable.
You should be pleased
with the effort
regardless of its outcome.
As someone who bears the same
fraternal scars of battle,
I hope that this defeat,
however bitter,
holds some solace.
He must have
that bullshit memorised
because it's
word-for-fucking-word
and the same
every single fucking time.
In all the men I've watched die
and laid to rest,
and there are multitudes,
I see a singularity.
It's in the eyes.
Their gaze is identical
in this moment.
Remorse, regret.
"What could I have done?
"What didn't I do?"
All our best intentions left to
bleed out with the rest of us.
But what if we could
remake our world whole
and erase our mistakes?
What if the ability
to rewrite history was real?
Adolf Hitler, Pearl Harbor...
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I've never lived past this point
so all this crap is new.
..in whose hands
would you entrust a tool
as powerful
as the Osiris Spindle?
I have your answer, Captain.
Mine.
A man brought to heel
by the brunt of human misery,
a man who understands,
as you do, the horrors of war.
Who better to oversee
and implement such a tool?
Exactly.
I am sorry about Dr Wells.
She took us as far as her
flawed ideology allowed her.
Sweet girl.
Blood on your hands
is what you wanted
when you came here, Captain,
and blood is what you have.
Just not mine.
Oh! That's really sharp.
There's not even any
blood on it. Is it a katana?
Katana? That's Japanese.
It's a Chinese sword.
Let's not make this about race.
It's a sword.
Brett, um, just...
I know three things now.
One - I'm gonna fuck that guy up
next time I see him.
Two - whatever I'm stuck in
is called the Osiris Spindle.
And three - Ventor has
no idea that it's working.
But somehow Jemma
put me inside this thing
and started it up, but why?
"She resurrected
her dead husband Osiris.
"Osiris became
lord of the dead...
"..and the afterlife."
[whirring]
I'm Osiris.
["Day After Day" by Badfinger]
[ticking]
♪ I remember
finding out about you... ♪
ROY: Jemma put me
in the Spindle to stop them,
to stop Ventor.
She needs me to keep
repeating this day until I do.
She had... she had faith.
Son of a bitch.
She still believed in me.
She knew I could beat him.
♪ Bring it home, baby,
make it soon
♪ I give my love to you... ♪
Hi.
[muffled] I need to know
how to fight with a sword.
I have no idea
what you just said.
Oh... OK.
I need to learn
how to fight with a sword.
[chuckles] There is something
intriguing
about you that I like.
I'm flying home to Shanghai
in the morning.
I would only have a day.
I think we can
get a lot done in a day.
♪ Looking out of my lonely room
♪ Day after day
♪ Bring it home, baby,
make it soon
♪ I give my love... ♪
I'm a beginner,
but I'm a quick learner.
It is the one who wields it
that makes it a weapon, Roy.
That sword is no more
an extension of you
than a set of car keys.
I've had some training,
but I'm willing to work hard.
In lesser hands,
the jian blade is just a flimsy
piece of forged steel.
But within
the most determined grip
and under the keenest eyes,
it becomes a weapon
of annihilation.
I've had a very good teacher,
but I need to learn more.
♪ Bring it home, baby,
make it soon
♪ I give my love
♪ To you. ♪
Hello, handsome.
Are you surrendering?
Mmm.
Hmm-hmm-hmm.
You're not really gonna fight me
with a sword, are you?
I do like your confidence.
Normally,
I'm a little more chatty.
I do have one thing to say.
I think it'll wait.
Shit's about to get steel.
[low tense music]
[grunts]
ROY: Huh!
Motherfucker.
[snarls]
[dramatic music]
[both grunt]
[Roy chuckles]
Hmm.
No!
Ugh...
Ohh!
What I wanted to say was
I am Roy
and Roy has done this.
[gunshot]
- [stab]
- BRETT: Ugh!
Wha... Wow.
Brett?
I smell muffins.
Do you smell muffins?
Ugh!
[groaning]
I'll just, uh, walk it off.
Now I'm blind.
[thud]
Looks like a 400-pound unicorn.
VENTOR: You slippery
son of a bi...
You gonna go for that gun?
I am not.
- Do you know why?
- No.
Because I'm gonna get
great satisfaction
beating the shit out of you.
[both grunting]
ROY: Arggh!
[screams]
[groans and pants]
How? How?
How do you think?
The Spindle. She activated it.
Jemma. She put me inside, pal.
She put me inside to stop you.
- Then you killed her...
- Ow!
..'cause she knew
what you were, Ventor.
A wannabe dictator
bent on a worldwide redo.
Fucking liberals.
Before she launched
her little Hail Mary,
did she bother to mention
that the Spindle reaction,
if maintained too long,
could destroy the entire planet?
Don't worry, dickhead,
the world comes to an end,
you won't be around to see it.
The Spindle gives us
the power of God
to re-create our whole world,
minus the tragedy.
Adolf Hitler, 9/11...
Shut up with
this bullshit speech.
The past is the past, Ventor.
It's designed to be left behind.
We live and we learn from it.
And this from an absentee
husband and failed father.
[Ventor groans]
I would've thought you'd have
more than a passing interest
in redoing things.
What about your son?
- My son?
- Young Joe, isn't it?
[Ventor chuckles]
If you've come
all this way to kill me,
well, then who's saving him?
[engine roars]
ROY: I never thought
Joe would be in danger.
I never thought
in a million years
that they'd ever target him.
I'll kill Ventor and every one
of those motherfuckers
a thousand times
if they hurt that kid.
OFFICER: Sir, sir!
Behind the barricade, sir.
You can't go that way, sir!
Hey, pal, I need you
behind the barricade. Pal!
[dramatic music]
How many times
have I let him die?
- [voice echoes] My son!
- You need to...
ROY: Get off me!
[grunting echoes]
My son!
No!
That's my son!
I didn't save my son!
No! No!
[explosion]
ROY: And there it is.
The end of the world.
Why not?
Mine's already over.
I can feel it.
Not just death,
but being unravelled.
Every part of me
splits and splits again,
along with everything else.
There's nowhere left to run,
and the one person
who could help is dead.
So what if I avenged her?
I'm... I'm the one
that killed her.
Not Ventor. Me. I did it.
I killed her when I ran
from my relationship.
I killed her when
I ran from raising our son.
I killed her
when I didn't call her back.
I'm the reason she's gone.
I'm the reason
Joe's gone.
I'm the reason the world ends.
What the hell's the point?
Why the hell should I even
bother trying?
Nothing will ever matter again.
Not when you've lost
everything you've loved.
Not when you're responsible
for the loss of all human life
as we know it.
Nice job, asshole.
[crack]
Can't you ever let me
sleep in just once?!
[machete clatters]
So this is it, then?
This is it, huh?
You're just gonna feel sorry
for yourself forever,
day in, day out?
You're not gonna do
a goddamn thing,
even if there isn't
a goddamn thing you can do?
No.
You are.
You're gonna do something.
["Turn Back The Hands Of Time"
by Tyrone Davis]
♪ If I had the chance
to start all over
♪ I would be wishing today
on a four-leaf clover
♪ And leaving would be
the last thing on my mind
♪ If I could turn back
the hands of time... ♪
ROY: Time means nothing now.
It's no longer
counting against you.
BOTH: I'm being car...!
You never got to know your son,
so if that's all that's left...
..it's more than
you ever deserved.
ROY: Hey, Joe!
Roy, what are you doing here?
What happened to you?
Eh, I fell off a building.
Skipping school?
Let me guess.
Pop-up eSport tournament?
JOE: How'd you know?
Where do you think I'm going?
- You're a gamer?
- Absolutely I'm a gamer.
I knew you were on your Xbox
every time I came over,
but I didn't wanna blow it
with your mom, you know?
Yeah.
I'm into, like, the old '80s
vintage side-scroller games
like 'Altered Beast'
and 'Double Dragon'.
- 'Street Fighter'?
- That's my favourite.
Mine too.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I like the new
stuff too, though. Uh...
Hey, Roy, you think Mom will be
pissed that I bailed on school?
You know what?
She'll be pissed.
But I'm gonna cover for you, OK?
- OK.
- No more skipping school.
- Cool?
- Cool.
Cool?
Cool.
Let's go play
some 'Street Fighter'.
- GAME: Fight!
- ROY: You're gonna die.
- JOE: No, you're gonna die.
- Yeah?
JOE: You're gonna die and fail.
- ROY: Oh!
- Oh, my bad.
Oh, but I'm still alive!
JOE: This game is so old.
What's it called? 'Glaca'?
- This game is broken.
- No, it's 'Galaga'. 'Galaga'.
Right in your face! Hey!
- What?
- I still won!
I got it. [laughs]
JOE: Ooh!
- [Roy groans]
- JOE: KO!
GAME: You win!
Why do you like
this game so much?
Well, there's a lot of people
that chase you
and you get to kill them.
- That was a power boost.
- That was a cool... arugula.
- Was that the arugula?
- 'Hadouken'!
- GAME: Hadouken!
- ROY: Duking again!
- [Joe sighs]
- Hadouken!
- JOE: How did you...
- Hadouken.
GAME: You win!
This is where it gets hard.
Yeah, get the girl,
get the girl.
JOE: Get her?
Ohh...
Tell you what.
Let me show you how it's done.
JOE: Man, these guys
keep coming.
You have no idea.
JOE: I'm not worried about it.
For a kid who
doesn't go to school
that much, you're pretty smart.
- I have my ways.
- Yeah.
You beat me again!
I'm pretty much the master!
ROY: All the years of this
that I missed...
I want it all back.
He has Jemma's looks,
her smarts, her sense of humour.
Thank God.
Then I see that kid laugh
and I see myself, just a flash.
To see my own face
smiling back at me, it just...
It breaks my heart.
[birds chirping]
I could do this forever,
and I just might.
We've ended this day
just like this
over a dozen times now.
Never gets old.
I like that he's sound asleep
when it all ends.
I like that he never stirs once.
[explosion]
I want to tell him
that I'm his father
like I did before,
but I'm scared.
I'm scared he won't
look at me that way again
and I won't see
what I saw in his eyes,
so I say nothing.
[birds chirping]
I wanna get a boat one day,
take Mom out in it.
She never gets out at all.
I just wish I could rent one.
Could we rent one?
- A boat?
- Yeah.
Take Mom out in it.
- I don't see why not.
- When?
Whenever. We can...
This is when I tell him
we can do it this weekend.
Then he sends his mom a text,
telling her that
we're all going sailing.
This is what usually happens.
Joey...
You know, your mom...
Yeah?
Do you know what your mom
was working on?
The Osiris Spindle.
Osiris Spindle.
You know what that does?
She can't talk about it
'cause it's, like,
super secret and whatever.
But I overheard her say
it could wipe out everything,
like the world, I guess,
if they weren't careful.
Do you believe that?
Yeah, I do.
I wish I didn't.
Your mom trusted me with
something and I let her down.
What do you mean?
Last night, your mom, she, um...
She didn't come home.
I know.
Does she have a new boyfriend?
[chuckles]
No.
No, there's no new boyfriend.
Did she know
I was ditching school?
'Cause it felt like
you were following me.
Yeah, well, I...
Not for that reason.
- Why, then?
- I... I don't know.
I saw you
and I wanted to talk to you.
We could catch up.
We haven't spoken to each other.
Why'd you think
I was following you?
Just something Mom said
this morning.
- Wait, what?
- On the phone. It was weird.
She said if I got into any
trouble that I should find you.
Joe, it's Mom.
Pick up the phone, please.
I didn't know
what she was talking about.
You spoke to Mom today?
If anything strange happens,
I want you to call Roy, OK?
What time?
I don't know. Um...
I'm gonna text you his number,
but call me back. Bye, baby.
Hey, bud, let me see your phone.
ROY: She was still alive
when I woke up.
Ventor hadn't killed her.
[gasps]
She wasn't dead yet.
[explosion]
Don't worry, son.
I'll come back for you.
I'm coming back for both of you.
[momentous music builds]
[groans]
You killed her.
How the hell
did you get in here?
Where is she?
Where is she?!
[melancholy music]
[Brett grunts]
Ugh!
Were you trying
to erase the evidence?
Trying to figure out
what she was doing,
how she was able
to initiate the Spindle...
- Shut your mouth, Brett!
- [gunshots]
Continue...
Continue!
We can't get
the Osiris Spindle to function.
Whatever she did
started a chain reaction
that we can't control.
She sabotaged it somehow
and it's not responding.
VENTOR: Son of a bitch.
The Spindle is working.
It's you. She made you
the missing mass.
Otherwise, how could you
have broken into this facility?
How...
..how many times
have you done this?
A lot.
It works.
[Ventor laughs]
ROY: She was alive at least
14 minutes after I woke up.
I have time to save her.
OK. Let's do this.
Jemma is the only one
who can stop this
and you have at least
14 minutes to reach her.
What the hell. Here we go.
["Foreplay/Long Time" by Boston]
The fucking asshole just jumped!
♪ It's been such
a long time... ♪
- [screams]
- Fly, motherfucker!
Fly!
♪ Time doesn't wait for me... ♪
I got 12.5 minutes.
Make this thing go faster.
Move!
♪ Sail on
♪ On a distant highway... ♪
ROY: Nice flying, dick!
♪ I've got to keep on
chasing a dream
♪ I've gotta be on my way
♪ Wish there was something
I could say... ♪
ROY: I want the big
knock-down, drag-out now.
The donnybrook.
The battle royale.
♪ Well, I'm taking my time
♪ I'm just movin' on... ♪
ROY: Bring 'em all on,
every last one of 'em,
so I can light 'em up
and lay waste.
♪ And I take what I find,
I don't want no more
♪ It's just outside
of your front door... ♪
ROY: 'Cause I've been
waiting for this
for a long fucking time.
[brattling]
♪ It's been such
a long time... ♪
Maybe too long.
Ha-ha!
I mean, you know,
I don't have all day.
♪ Well, I get so lonely
♪ When I am without you
♪ But in my mind,
deep in my mind
♪ I can't forget about you
♪ Ohh
♪ Good times
♪ Faces that remind me, yeah
♪ I'm tryin' to forget your name
♪ And leave it all behind me
♪ You're coming back
to find me, yeah
♪ Well, I'm taking my time
♪ I'm just movin' on
♪ You'll forget about me
after I've been gone
♪ And I'll take what I find
♪ I don't want no more
♪ It's just outside
of your front door
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah... ♪
ROY: Hey, Brett!
♪ It's been such
a long time... ♪
Ooh!
♪ It's been such a long time! ♪
- [Jemma gasps]
- VENTOR: Ugh!
You came for me.
You did it.
How many times did it take?
Just one.
We don't have much time.
Come on.
I couldn't tell you. They were
watching me, monitoring me.
I had to sneak around
the lab all night.
I barely got that book to you.
It was just enough.
[low whirring]
I think Ventor
sent men after Joe.
There's no-one left.
They're all gone, Jemma.
Joe's fine.
He's skipping school to go
to Gamer-Con, but he's OK.
How do you know that?
[tender music]
He's got a crush on a girl
in his class named Camille
who he showed
all the bus routes in school to,
but he's afraid to ask her
to be his girlfriend.
He and his friend Wyatt,
they lied about their age
a couple of weeks ago
to enter a paintball tournament.
You asked him about a welt
on his neck.
He said he got it
from a bug bite.
He, uh... he fractured his wrist
last month skateboarding
and now it makes
this weird, funny...
- Clicking noise.
- ..clicking sound.
He loves dogs, especially pugs,
and he thinks you two
should rescue one.
He did a watercolour version
of Van Gogh's 'Starry Night'
about a year ago
for your birthday
'cause he knows
that's your favourite painting.
He thinks Mom works too much,
doesn't smile enough.
Oh, but that boy
loves you so much.
How do I stop this, Jemma?
It's not about stopping, Roy.
It's about restarting.
I made your dimensions,
your DNA,
specific to the missing mass
within the Spindle.
What does that mean?
It means you have to enter
the Spindle's core,
then, theoretically,
the time-space continuum
should reset and resume.
Theoretically?
I don't know.
I honestly don't, Roy.
I mean, this whole thing's
just so cobbled together.
I was just trying
to stop Ventor.
I didn't even know it worked
until you showed up.
You have to remember
I just saw you yesterday.
And I haven't seen you
in forever.
I didn't know what else to do,
where else to turn.
I just knew
the man you were, Roy.
I know the man you are.
But I don't know what'll happen
to you if you go in there.
ROY: I know
what happens if I don't.
You saw it,
the end of the world.
Yeah.
What was it like?
It was everything
you imagined it to be,
only a million times worse.
Will it go forward if I...
walk through this thing?
Is it gonna reset?
Are you and Joe gonna be safe?
If you return your mass
to the core, it should.
You may not make it.
You may cease to be.
Well, then...
..give me a kiss
and tell me you love me.
[music rises]
I love you.
[deep whirring]
Wait for me, yeah?
I will.
What the hell. Here we go.
[whooshing]
[momentous music]
[whooshing and vibrating]
[ticking]
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
["Only Time" by Clarence Ashe]
♪ Those cigarette ashes
♪ Her empty glass
♪ These things seem to tell me
♪ That it's over at last
♪ Her parting kiss
♪ Brought tears to my eyes
♪ Was it goodnight
♪ Or was it goodbye?
♪ Only time
♪ Only time can tell
♪ No, no, baby,
only time can tell
♪ The wrinkled up sofa
♪ Scuff marks on the floor
♪ Shows where she was sitting
♪ A moment ago
♪ She's never left
♪ This early before
♪ Was it a sign
♪ She'll be back no more?
♪ Only time
♪ Only time can tell
♪ No, no, baby
♪ I felt a change
♪ The moment she came
♪ Walking through my front door
♪ Right now, baby
♪ Her conversation
♪ Was almost the same,
but still I could tell
♪ That something was wrong,
the feeling had changed
♪ My, my, my, my, my, my baby
♪ I'll empty those ashtrays
♪ And her glass, I'll put away
♪ I'll straighten up the sofa
♪ Scuff marks out of place
♪ But will I ever
♪ Erase from my mind
♪ The way she looked
♪ When she left me behind?
♪ Only time
♪ Only time can tell
♪ My, my baby,
only time can tell
♪ I just wanna say
one thing, darling... ♪