(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GENTLE MUSIC CONTINUES)
COXSWAIN: Press.
Legs through.
Stay together.
(GRUNTING)
As one.
In. Through.
(BOAT ENGINE WHIRRING)
Legs through.
- (MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
- (GIRLS IN BOAT WHOOPING)
BOY: Oh, man!
(DUCK QUACKS)
(GRUNTING)
- (GIRLS WHOOPING)
- (MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
(GIRL SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
(LAUGHING AND WHOOPING)
(GRUNTS) What the heck?
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
WOMAN: I swear that boy's
gonna be the death of me.
Every time I fix it,
he rips it again.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYS)
(CAR HORN HONKS)
PROFESSOR: Engineering
design is different
from other areas of creativity
in that, you must be
able to actually build
what you imagine.
And then make sure it
works as you designed.
The design process is
structured to help direct
your creativity.
Now, uh...
(CHALK WRITING ON BOARD)
What kinda engineer
you wanna be?
I'm thinking mechanical for me
'cause I like building things.
- Mm-hmm.
- You wanna partner up on...
Something you two gentlemen
would like to share with us?
Or can I continue?
Sorry.
(STUDENTS LAUGH QUIETLY)
(SNICKERS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
WOMAN: Thank you. MAN:
Awesome. Thank you.
(LAUGHTER)
MAN: Okay, I just
need one more.
Let's see.
Uh, you.
That's all I need
today, fellas. Sorry.
(MEN GRUMBLING)
WOMAN: Morning. BOY: Morning.
This was in my box this morning.
Okay, it looks like
you still owe a balance
on this semester.
Yeah, well, I paid half already
and they said I could
pay the other half later.
Afraid later has
arrived, Mr. Rantz.
Maybe a part-time
job would help.
(SCOFFS) I've been looking.
Well, there's a
board down the hall.
I can give you two weeks.
After that, you will
need to consider
other educational options.
Thanks.
It's a waste of time. I
called every number up here.
And that nanny job,
all filled before
semester even started.
I check every day to
get a jump on a new one,
but there hadn't been any.
I'm staying with my aunt
till I can afford a place.
I spend half my day pulling
cat hair off of my clothes.
I hate cats.
You like 'em?
Cats, I mean.
I, uh, never thought
much about 'em.
I hate 'em.
GIRL: Thought I
saw you in class.
- You remember me?
- Mm-hmm.
All right. Then,
what's my name?
Uh, Joyce Simdars.
- And you're Joe Rantz.
- Uh-huh.
I remember because you
had a huge crush on me
in the fourth grade.
- No, I didn't.
- Yeah, yeah, you did.
You made me this
pretty little card
with some flowers stuffed in it.
Right before my family
went away to Olympia.
- Uh...
- Are you one of those people
who can't eat when
you're nervous?
- I'm not nervous.
- No?
So, what are you
doing here, Joe?
I'm trying to learn,
uh, engineering.
Hmm.
I'm gonna be a teacher.
Mostly here just to get
away from home, though.
You remember my mother?
Sorta. Always had a
Bible in her hand.
Yeah. (LAUGHS)
Unless she's throwing it at you.
- (CHUCKLES)
- BOY: You like rowboats?
You know, like, paddlin' 'em.
- Who's this?
- I'm Roger.
Hi, Roger. I'm Joyce.
This is Joe, but he's not
real talkative right now
'cause he's a
little bit nervous.
- No, I'm not. No, I'm not.
- He is a little nervous.
JOE: I'm not nervous.
We might be able to make
some money if you can row.
- GIRL: Joyce, you ready?
- Oh. Gotta go, boys.
Nice seeing you again, Joe.
Roger.
By the way,
did you ever get
over that crush?
- (GIRLS LAUGH)
- GIRL: Come on, let's go.
(WHISTLES)
She's a looker, huh?
So, what's that about
making some money?
Yeah, the rowing team.
You're on it, you
get a part-time job
including a cheap place to live.
I could get free of them cats.
All you gotta do
is make the team.
How hard can that be?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
How many make the team?
Hey, how many, uh...
How many fellas get picked?
Eight, I think.
Eight?
What's he say?
He didn't know.
(DOOR SLIDES OPEN)
All right, listen up.
I'm Coach Ulbrickson.
Well, that's Coach Bolles,
Coach Brown.
Now, you're all here
because we're looking
for the eight most qualified
young men to fill out JV boat.
That means most of you
will not be chosen.
In fact, the majority
of you will most likely
walk away on your own
within the next few weeks,
'cause your bodies will hurt,
minds will tire,
and you'll decide
this dream of yours
to compete against the
greatest crews in the world
is just not worth it.
There's no shame in that.
Eight-man crew
is the most difficult
team sport in the world.
The average human body is just
not meant for such things.
It's just not capable
of such things.
But average is not gonna
get a seat on my boat.
So, good luck.
Okay. Fall into two lines.
Registration on the left.
Uniforms on the right.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
That was a beautiful
speech, Coach.
- Name?
- Uh, Joe Rantz.
Joe, you ever crewed before?
Uh... Um...
Row. You ever rowed before?
No. No. Uh...
How much does the job pay
once you're on the team?
Go pick up your gear over there.
- To your right. Next.
- Name?
Roger Morris.
BOLLES: Roger, you
ever crewed before?
ROGER: No.
BOLLES: All right.
Pick up your gear
across the way.
You'll be divided into groups
and rotate through
training stations.
When you hear your number
called, follow the coach.
One through 16, you're with me,
17 through 32 with
Coach Matthews,
33 to 48 with me.
Line up. (TAPS BANISTER)
You got any idea
what we're in for?
I don't know.
Good. Me either.
(PERCUSSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
One through 16, come on.
BROWN The average
adult man is capable
of taking in roughly four
liters of oxygen per minute.
An oarsman must be able to
consume as much as eight.
You have to teach your
bodies to do that.
- (STUDENTS GRUNTING)
- We'll do 50 push-ups,
followed by 50
sit-ups and 50 jacks.
We'll keep doing sets of 50
till it's time to
change stations.
Eight on each side.
Feet in stretchers.
Lace 'em up.
Let's take Old Nero out.
All right, on my count,
straight backs, use your legs.
Twelve! Don't just slap the
water. Roll your wrists.
BROWN: Up, down.
Up, down.
(STUDENTS PANTING)
(DISTANTLY) Four,
five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten.
Stroke, two, three, four.
Catch, drive, finish, recovery.
Next station. Everybody out.
BROWN: Up, down.
Up, down.
Switch!
All set?
MATHEWS: Up, down.
- Up, down.
- (PANTING)
BOLLES: There's four parts
to a stroke, gentlemen,
not three, okay?
Catch, drive,
finish, and recovery.
You can't skip any of 'em.
And you know why we're not
going in a straight line?
'Cause number 22 here
is the only one that's
listening to me.
Catch, drive,
finish, recovery.
That's better.
All right. Let's pick
up the pace to 18.
Lot of tall timber
in this bunch, Coach.
Few boys there could even
push your varsity crew.
It's hard to judge off one day.
Still, you had to see enough
to make you almost
finally crack a smile?
Yeah, I'll let you know at
the end of the season, huh?
Olympic year, this year,
so ideally, they'll
stretch longer than most.
Olympic year? I
didn't realize.
(CHUCKLES)
MAN: I spoke with Coach
Ebright down in Cali.
He's sure aware of it.
Feels good about
his chances, too.
ULBRICKSON: Oh, yeah?
MAN: Any first impressions
you'd like to see in print?
ULBRICKSON: You know I
don't read the paper, Royal.
JOE: Excuse me, Coach.
If you're looking for tips, you're gonna have
to get 'em in practice like everybody else.
No, sir. I was just
wondering how much this paid.
Say again?
They said there was a job
included if you make the team?
I just need to know
if it's gonna cover
the rest of my tuition.
Yeah, I'm sure it will.
Hey, you just
concentrate for now
- on making the squad, son.
- Thank you, sir.
Now, there's a question I bet
those Ivy League
coaches never get.
Speakin' of,
I sure hope this year
goes better than the last.
No one's rooting for
your boys more than me.
- Good luck, Coach.
- And you, Royal.
Did you go grab some food?
Ah, I'm not hungry.
I got enough for us
both if you want it.
Not that hungry.
I'll see you later.
MAN: I appreciate it.
(MAN 2 COUGHS)
BOY: There you go.
Here you go, sir. Thank you.
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CUTLERY CLACKING)
WOMAN: How's your
chicken? ULBRICKSON: Hmm?
Great. Thanks.
Yeah, that's a pork
chop you're eating.
Ah.
Sorry.
So, I saw Royal Brougham today.
And he made sure to tell me
that Ky Ebright's squad
is strong this year.
Cal is always strong.
And you always worry.
(CHUCKLES)
How'd your new boys look?
Well, it's too early to say.
There's definitely a lot of 'em.
That's good. Nice big
stable to choose from.
- If enough of them last.
- The best ones will.
- Just like you did.
- Mm.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS LOUDLY)
(GRUNTS, SIGHS)
What's wrong with you?
Nothing, just a little stiff.
Yeah, looks it. How come?
Rowed boats till it
almost killed us.
What?
PROFESSOR: Page
43 in your texts.
So, in solving the framework,
what does it mean to reflect?
(STUDENT SNORING)
(GIRL SNICKERS)
(SNORING CONTINUES)
(JOE GASPS)
(SMACKS LIPS)
Excuse me, young man.
Would you like me to speak
quieter so you can rest?
I feel like that's
maybe a trick question.
- (LAUGHTER)
- Quiet!
Pay attention or
go home to sleep.
You can't do both in here.
(WHISPERS) You're
welcome, Joe Rantz.
Thank you.
- (LIVELY JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
BROWN: Three.
Four.
Push, then pull. Push...
Up, down!
BOLLES: 48 and 12 on the bow.
Yeah. I'm thinkin'...
(ALL GRUNTING)
What about Morris in
the six behind Rantz?
- (ALL GRUNTING)
- (WHISTLE BLOWS)
(PANTING)
(RETCHES)
Keep time with me.
Stroke, two, three,
four. Stroke, two...
(PANTING)
(LIVELY JAZZ MUSIC CONTINUES)
Come on, boys!
Who wants it more?
Keep driving those legs!
Do not let 22 beat you!
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
You still remember me?
Mm-hmm.
Wasn't sure.
Haven't seen you much lately.
I just been busy with stuff.
- Rowing stuff?
- Mostly.
JOYCE: Hmm.
I heard Roger say that they're
announcing the team today.
Are you gonna make it?
There's lot of guys tryin'.
You wanna take me on a
boat ride when you do?
Sure.
ULBRICKSON: Gentlemen,
I wanna thank you
all for comin' out
and giving your best effort.
Every single one of
you left standing
has performed admirably.
Unfortunately, only a few of
you can be chosen to continue.
Coach Bolles.
Hume.
Hunt.
McMillin.
Day.
- Morris.
- (GASPS SOFTLY)
White.
Adam.
Rantz.
Coy, you're the reserve.
We thank the rest of you for
your time and your effort.
All right, then.
Go and celebrate.
I will see you on
the water tomorrow.
Well done.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(STUDENTS CHEERING
AND LAUGHING)
That's my favorite part.
Come on, boys.
Let's go.
Now lift 'em up.
DAY: It's all this guy
talks about, his Dodge.
(LAUGHTER)
ADAM: Hey, listen, I've
done so much rowing.
I knew you'd made it.
I'm glad one of us did.
Ah, you were always in the bag.
When Coach called my name,
my knees almost buckled.
I wonder what seats
they'll put us in.
I just want the stroke.
That's Hume's
seat. Guaranteed.
Hey, you're not a mute, are you?
'Cause I've never once
heard you say nothin'.
No.
He doesn't need to talk,
the way he pulls that oar.
Yeah, Chuck, maybe you should pull more
and talk less, you want that stroke seat.
I don't care where they put me,
as long as I'm in
there somewhere.
We're all in there somewhere.
Yeah.
(SINGING) Bow
down to Washington
(LAUGHTER)
Bow down to Washington
Mighty are the men who wear
the purple and the gold
Joyfully we welcome them
within the victor's fold
We will carve our names
in the Hall of Fame
To preserve the
memory of our devotion
So, heaven help the
foes of Washington
They're trembling at the
feet of mighty Washington
Our boys are there with bells
Their fighting blood excels
It's harder to push them
over the lines than pass...
(SOFT CLACK ON WINDOW)
- JOE: Hey.
- Hi.
You, uh...
You wanna go for a boat ride?
Now?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay.
JOE: Catch, drive,
- finish, recovery.
- (GIGGLES)
You gotta do all four
before you can start again.
That's better. You
gotta feather next.
Feathering? What's feather?
Here, look.
You roll your wrists
to spin the oar.
- You see?
- Mm.
Now, try again.
(WATER SPLASHING)
- You're a natural.
- (CHUCKLES)
I thought you said you were
gonna take me on a boat ride.
All right, scooch over.
All right.
Do you like it? Rowing?
Well,
gettin' a job out of it.
And a room. So, I guess.
Who else made the team?
Roger, Shorty, some others.
You know, they put the
races on the radio.
Everybody listens.
Yeah, they took,
uh, some photos.
- Asked a bunch of questions.
- What kinds of questions?
It's just, you know,
where we're from,
stuff like that.
Did you tell them the truth?
Mm. Mostly.
(CHUCKLES)
You're all gonna be famous.
Then you really will
forget about me.
I don't think I
could if I tried.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
You get to row us back to shore.
We have class in the morning.
- Which bed you want?
- Couldn't care less.
(GRUNTS)
- (EXHALES)
- Oh, nice.
We get to keep these, right?
Long as we stay on the team.
ULBRICKSON: Each seat on the
boat has its own purpose.
Like eight separate parts
of one great racehorse.
Morris in one, Day in two,
and Adam in the three.
Your technique will keep the
boat on its proper course.
And four, five, and six
are like the engine room.
That is the power.
White, McMillin, and Hunt.
Now, Rantz is our seven.
So, you set the pace
with Hume, the stroke.
And every good
racehorse has a jockey.
Glenn Morry...
Come on, Glenn.
Is our coxswain.
Now, he calls the strategy
set up by myself
and Coach Bolles.
He'll give you rein when
he wants you to run,
he'll pull you back
to slow you down.
And when the time is right,
he'll get out his whip.
- Hey, fellas.
- (CREW GREETS)
ULBRICKSON: Okay, time
to get in the water.
(ROUSING MUSIC PLAYING)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
(ROUSING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Let's go again!
(SHOWER RUNNING)
BOY: Hey, junior boat,
you tired after your first day?
(LAUGHTER)
BOY 2: He'll never make it.
BOY 3: Don't take it so hard.
Hey, where you
going? Come back.
I hate those assholes.
BOY 4: You gotta learn
to pace yourself.
(DOOR OPENS)
- It's Joe, isn't it?
- Mm-hmm.
Most of you boys don't
have an interest in a boat
until you can sit in it.
You like to work with wood?
Yeah, my father did some.
He used to make things.
Nothing like this,
just porches and stuff.
I helped him fix up
an old canoe once.
I'm sure he and your mother
must be very proud of you now.
Making the team.
(CHUCKLES QUIETLY)
This is for you boys.
Your racing shell.
Always welcome to give
me a hand with it.
If you find some free time.
(CHUCKLES) No, I
didn't mean right now.
You should rest up tonight.
I'm okay.
ULBRICKSON: Technique is
more important than power.
You have to be able
to pull a perfect oar,
stroke after stroke.
It's called swing.
When all eight are rowing
in such perfect unison
that no single action
is out of sync with
the rest of the boat.
Then you aren't
fighting each other.
You're moving with less effort.
Each one of your
strokes is worth
one and a half of
the other boat's.
Most crews never find it.
But when they do,
rowing is more
poetry than sport.
White and Day, switch.
Rantz, Adam,
switch back.
Row!
- Row!
- Come on!
MORRY: Row! BOLLES:
Row through the lake!
MORRY: Row! More!
ULBRICKSON: What, did you
forget everything you learned
in the last three years?
Brown, you're still skying.
Billings, are you the
stroke? You're rushing.
You have seven men behind
you, all chasing the boat.
34 strokes.
You're fine at 34 strokes.
Anything higher
and you fall apart.
34 strokes, you don't beat Cal.
34 strokes,
you don't win at Poughkeepsie.
You certainly don't
get to Germany.
You know who you
beat with 34 strokes?
The JV boat.
Maybe.
What are you guys waiting
for? Get back in the boat.
You guys, you're gonna
get back out there
and you're gonna do it again
until you get it right!
- (KNOCK AT DOOR)
- Hope I'm not intruding, Al.
Not at all, Ben. Come
on in. Take a seat.
Great timing.
Just going through
the equipment budget
to send over to your committee.
Nothing unreasonable.
Some pieces for the gymnasium.
And the five-year-old uniforms
are startin' to look
a little ragged.
Ah, we'll see what we can do.
Committee's meeting next week.
More wins usually means
more money from the alumni.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Sure.
So, how are our
boys doing, Coach?
Early to say, but solid.
Oh, they've been workin' hard.
My boy, Bo, had 'em training
- all off season.
- Hmm.
- Think they're gonna make a real run at Cal this year.
- I hope we can.
We got a good junior boat to
push 'em, too. You should...
It'd be nice to finally hang
a banner up at our place
instead of letting
Cal have 'em all.
We'll do our best, sir.
And an Olympic
medal to go with it.
Bo says his boat's got a shot.
If we work hard.
And catch some breaks.
Winners make our own
breaks in life, Coach.
And we need this.
It's now or never.
Hmm.
MCMILLIN: "If we
shadows have offended
"Think but this,
and all is mended.
"That you have but
slumbered here...
"While these
visions did appear."
- Thank you.
- (MAN 2 COUGHS)
It's some fella called
Shakespeare, right?
You know, music people
should have to take
care of their own trash.
MCMILLIN: Better than
the cafeteria last night.
I mean, God, I almost
couldn't eat today.
You see that old food, all
mushed around like that?
Eugh!
You ever notice how
under the girls' tables,
it's always the worst?
When you look close,
girls are nasty.
You don't realize it 'cause
of their nice dresses
and their hair's all fixed up.
But I'll clean under 10 boys'
tables before I do one...
(PLAYING GENTLE MUSIC)
Oh, Don, there
anything you can't do?
Keep goin'.
(RESUMES PLAYING GENTLE MUSIC)
(SINGING) Ain't we got fun?
The rent's unpaid, dear
BOYS: We haven't a car
In any way, dear
We'll stay as we are
- (BOYS SCATTING)
- Even if we owe the grocer
Ain't we got fun?
What about Morris in
the six behind Rantz
and Hunt in the one?
We tried that last week.
(SIGHS) I don't know.
On paper, this should work.
BOLLES: Better than just work.
You put them in singles
against 100 other kids,
I'd bet on that being the top
eight finishers out there.
ULBRICKSON: That's
the problem.
They have a hard
time remembering
they aren't in sculls,
especially Rantz.
They're a strong a
group as I've ever seen
come through here
and they might also be the
worst crew I've ever seen.
It's a bad mix.
It's my fault.
Well, maybe those names
aren't the problem.
Sometimes young horses
need a louder jockey.
- (KNOCKING)
- You wanted to see me, Coach?
ULBRICKSON: Close the door.
Sit down, Bobby.
You know why I called you here?
My guess is you need someone
to help you beat Cal.
(SIGHS) Let me explain
something to you.
I'm giving you a second chance.
You're gonna drive the JV boat.
- JV?
- Yeah, that's right.
Now, listen to me.
You're gonna do what I
tell you, when I tell you.
And if I see you goin' off
on your own, then you're out.
For good this time.
You understand?
- Yeah, I do.
- All right.
Get out.
(ROUSING MUSIC PLAYING)
Come on!
- (ROWING)
- Your hands are too high!
Fix the catch.
One catch, let's go.
Look like a team, fellas.
Legs through, eyes up.
Legs through.
You guys are out
of sync. Find Hume.
Take it off Hume.
Watch those blade heights.
Hey, Rantz, you with
us? Get with Hume.
Legs through.
Legs through. Come on!
Day, you're catching
too high. Lower.
Morris, you're late.
Enough! Way-nuff! Way-nuff!
(CREW GASPING IN EXHAUSTION)
(COUGHING)
(EXHALES)
Yeah, good ride.
And my favorite part
is how my nuts vibrated
when you guys were all hitting
the water at different times.
We were moving slow as shit,
but the sensation was nice.
Screw you, Moch.
BOBBY: No, dandy,
you're the one screwed.
Coach told me if you guys
don't get yourselves
figured out,
you're not only
missing the regatta,
you're not racing
at all this year.
That's a whole hell
of a lot of work
to just do nothing with.
So, feel like trying it again?
I'm ready.
(CREW PANTING)
That's good.
Always with the grain.
How's the crew coming along?
Lot harder than I expected.
Well, that's what
practice is for.
Coaches will have you
ready for the regatta.
Your folks gonna make it?
My mother, she passed
when I was young.
And my pop, he had to move off
several years ago to find work.
Kinda lost touch.
Who brought you up?
Pop figured I was
okay on my own.
Hmm.
How old were you?
Almost 14.
Him and my stepmom,
they had two young
boys to care for.
There was no work around Sequim.
Worked out best for everybody.
BOBBY: Legs through.
Legs through.
Legs through. Soften
the shoulders.
Eyes up.
Stay loose.
Shoulders down, Joe.
Stay low.
Stay loose.
Eyes up.
BOLLES: Better?
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
BOBBY: As one.
As one.
Put the pressure
in the footplate.
Drive!
Here she is, boys.
Maybe the finest
George has ever made.
Now, this is your new home.
Treat her that way.
- Care for her. Protect her.
- (WHISTLES)
Most of all, you
better respect her.
All right, suit up
and get out there.
You race against Cal in a week.
Won't let you down, Coach.
(STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING)
Welcome to a beautiful
day at Lake Washington
for the annual showdown
between the Washington Huskies
and the Cal Bears of Berkeley
in the Pacific Coast Regatta.
And just as it has been
for the past 30 years,
the two-mile race will
extend from Sand Point
up to Sheridan Beach.
We have 100,000 race
fans gathered here
for what is sure to be
another maritime battle
the likes of which we haven't
seen since New Orleans.
And in the purple and gold,
Washington Huskies coach,
Al Ulbrickson, is bringing
back a strong senior team
and an inexperienced
junior boat,
in hopes of reversing a
devastating season last year.
Without a doubt, he's
facing stiff competition.
Legendary Coach Ky
Ebright has once again
brought two strong boats.
He's called his junior crew
possibly the best young
oarsmen he has ever had.
(WHOOPING)
(EXCITED CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
MAN: Let's go, Washington!
(GIRLS SQUEAL)
GIRL: Hi, Roger.
Don't try and do too
much. Listen to Moch.
Stay close, and we'll
hope Cal makes a mistake.
BOBBY: Stay calm
with the body.
Hold your hands up...
- Inspiring.
- Hmm?
Uh, you missed the
part where I told 'em
just to try not to tip over.
ANNOUNCER: Ladies
and gentlemen,
please take your seats.
Five minutes till the start.
(CROWD CHATTERING
AND CHEERING)
Hey, uh, my boys are feeling
a little under the weather, Al.
I hope you take it easy on us.
Not even if I believed you, Ky.
ANNOUNCER: Both teams
are in position.
(ALL CHEERING)
Winds are out of the north
at five miles an hour.
The temperature is
a mild 71 degrees.
(CHEERING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
BOBBY: All right, boys.
You heard Ulbrickson.
Stick close and hope
they make a mistake.
That's his way of saying
don't embarrass him
'cause that's what he
thinks you're gonna do.
I say the hell with all that.
All these people didn't just
come to see you stick close.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Let's show Ulbrickson
what's in this boat.
Ready?
- (ALL ROWING IN UNISON)
- (WATER SPLASHING)
ANNOUNCER: The oarsmen
are at the ready.
- Row!
- BOBBY: Row!
ANNOUNCER: And they're off!
(WATCH TIMER TICKING)
ROYAL: Washington is
slow off the block.
(CHEERING)
Step on 'em early! 38!
Let's go! Good.
Yeah, we got 'em.
All right. Give me
a nice, easy 28.
In and through.
And pull!
ROYAL: Washington's JV boat
is racing for the first
time in competition.
ANNOUNCER: Cal breaks
early. COXSWAIN: Easy work.
ANNOUNCER: Cal has half
a boat on Washington.
Easy, boys. Nice and easy.
ROYAL: Cal jumps out
to an early lead.
Washington is
struggling to keep pace.
That's right. Just
keep them in sight.
BOBBY: Don't sky
the blade, McMillin!
In, through.
Shoulders loose.
In the legs!
ANNOUNCER: Cal opening up
a full boat on Washington.
And at the quarter mark,
it's Cal up a full boat.
Come on! Come on, Washington!
COXSWAIN: We got
this, boys! Come on.
BOBBY: Through.
In, through.
Don't panic, Bobby.
BOBBY: Don't rush.
ROYAL: Cal still showing
no signs of slowing down.
Washington is getting its
first taste of competition.
Something Coach Ulbrickson
can hope to build on.
(CROWD SHOUTING ENCOURAGEMENT)
Through! In, and through!
Push! Push!
All right, here we go, boys.
Give me 35.
Let's show 'em what we got.
Build! Build it!
What are they doing? I said
let Cal come back to them.
ANNOUNCER: Now at
the halfway mark.
The Huskies with a burst.
Just passing the halfway point
and Washington is surging.
Oh, you better be right, Moch.
In, through!
- In, through!
- ROYAL: Here they come.
Here comes Washington.
Eyes up.
- Eyes up!
- Push!
ANNOUNCER: They're past
the three-quarter mark.
Cal and Washington
are neck and neck!
- Go!
- BOBBY: Row!
Stay loose!
Push! Push!
ROYAL: Cal is falling back.
BOBBY: Let's go!
ROYAL: Washington is
picking up the pace!
ANNOUNCER: Washington's
passing Cal!
ROYAL: And look at this.
The Washington boat
has taken the lead!
(EXCITED CHEERING)
Washington by half a boat!
- Row! Let's go!
- Come on!
ROYAL: Two hundred
meters to go!
- Washington is pulling ahead!
- Twenty more strokes!
Come on, come on.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Come on! Go!
ROYAL: Washington
by a full boat!
BOBBY: In and through!
ANNOUNCER: One hundred meters!
- Fifteen more!
- (CHEERING)
Come on! Come on!
Through! Ten more!
ANNOUNCER: Fifty meters!
- (ALL GRUNTING HEAVILY)
- ROYAL: Fifty meters!
Washington is going to do it!
BOBBY: You got this!
In and through!
Push!
ANNOUNCER: Twenty-five meters!
(WATCH TIMER TICKING)
ROYAL: And there's the flag!
Washington has done it!
Washington's junior boat has
won their first competition!
Yeah!
ROYAL: What a promising
start for these young men!
Jesus!
I got nine seconds
under the course record.
Same.
And the final third is
faster than the first.
Where the hell did
that come from?
(CHUCKLES)
I guess that little runt
knew what he was doin'.
- Yeah!
It's all you, boys!
All you!
- Yeah!
- (WHOOPING)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(WHOOPING)
One!
Two!
Three!
(LAUGHING AND CHEERING)
I like your hat.
Thank you. Thank you.
MAN: Come on!
Washington!
Come on!
HUNT: Oh, my God.
Hi.
I could get used to this.
How did your first win feel?
Great.
Next one's gonna be even faster.
(LAUGHING)
(BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING)
GIRL: How did you go so fast?
HUNT: Oh, we just rowed
as quick as we could.
It must have been hard,
even though you're strong.
You get tired?
Yeah, yeah, it was pretty rough.
Too tired to go someplace quiet
and show me how you did it?
Oh, hell no.
You know, this might
make all the times
Morris puked on
my back worth it.
I got this today.
Some fellow in a suit
just gave it to me.
- Said us winning made him so happy, he wanted me to have...
- Shoot, we all made him happy, Gordo.
Kid in my algebra class
offered to do my
homework for me.
- I let the sap do it.
- You should.
We keep on winnin',
we're gonna have it
made in this place.
- You did so good today.
- Huh?
I said you did so...
I said you did so good today.
Thank you.
It was... It was fun.
What?
(BIG BAND MUSIC CONTINUES)
Come here. I said it was fun.
Do you wanna go someplace quiet?
(SIGHS)
(BIG BAND MUSIC CONTINUES)
Watcha doin'?
I'm watching.
Why aren't you
talking to anybody?
I'm not much of a talker.
Ah.
Hey, look over there.
You see that beanpole
in the glasses?
Yeah.
He's studying Latin.
- Oh.
- Latin.
You don't have to say much.
Listen, Hume.
Tonight, not tomorrow
night, or next week.
Tonight is your best shot.
You go on. I think I'm okay.
(GROANS) Christ sake.
(BIG BAND MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- Hey, listen up!
We got a musician in our midst.
With a little encouragement,
we might just get him to
give us some live music.
Don Hume!
Get up here. Get up here.
- ADAM: Come on, Don!
- (CROWD APPLAUDING)
No. No.
- Hey, watch out.
- No, no, no, no, no.
Bobby, get the stool.
The piano man.
John, John, John, John,
John, John, John, John.
- No, no, no, no, no.
- There we go.
All ready for you
there, maestro.
- Let's hear it for Don!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
Don Hume.
GIRL: Come on, Don!
GIRL 2: We know you can do it.
(CHEERING SUBSIDES)
- Come on, Don.
- Come on, Donnie.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(PLAYING UPBEAT MELODY)
(JOYCE GIGGLES)
I don't think that
I should be here.
He can't be in here.
Oh, shut up, Carolyn.
I saw you smoking at
your window last week.
(JOYCE GIGGLES)
- It was too loud in there.
- JOE: Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
People are happy.
They're having fun.
Yeah, because of you.
Okay, I'm changing.
Eyes on the wall.
Right.
Did you know you were gonna win?
JOE: No. My arms,
they were shaking.
I was so nervous.
JOYCE: We were all
screaming so loud.
The radio said it
was the fastest ever.
Yeah, that's what Coach told us.
(SWITCH CLICKS)
I bet you win every race.
Just don't get all
stuck-up and everything.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
I just kept that in case
I ever ran into you again.
And had to, um...
prove that you had that
crush on me, like I said.
(SOFT MUSIC CONTINUES)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
WOMAN: Miss Simdars,
open this door.
You... You should go.
You should go. You need
to go. You need to go.
Miss Simdars, open this
door right now, young lady.
If you have a male
visitor in there,
well, you know the consequences.
One minute! (SQUEALS SOFTLY)
- JOE: What?
- Is that too far?
- No.
- You're fine.
Miss Simdars!
STUDENTS: (SINGING)
Ain't we got fun?
Tax collector's getting closer
Still, we got fun
There's nothing surer
The rich get rich and
the poor get poorer
In the meantime, in between time
Ain't we got fun?
(ALL CHEERING)
Well done!
Okay! Yeah!
BOBBY: Don Hume,
ladies and gentlemen.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
(PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
- Harvard, Yale?
- Mm-hmm.
Both have put up times we
haven't gotten close to.
That's how it usually goes.
Kids back East are in boats
before they're in shoes.
Schools just have more
talent to choose from.
That's what money buys you.
(SMACKS LIPS)
We need an edge, Tom.
(WISTFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(RIVETING MUSIC PLAYING)
BOBBY: Through.
In and through.
And through!
Eyes up!
In and through!
- Stand tall.
- (WATCH CLICKS)
Legs through.
In and through.
In, through.
Legs through.
Way-nuff!
Everybody else tires and
they just get stronger.
(WHOOPING)
That's the third time they
beat the varsity squad.
ROGER: Maybe next time.
BOLLES: I just think
it's too big of a risk.
Poughkeepsie is more than just
the championship this year.
It's for the Olympics.
I know what the race means, Tom.
Experience counts for
something in big races.
Half those guys on varsity
competed at
Poughkeepsie last year.
- And they lost.
- They're better this year.
If you didn't know their ages,
you didn't know how long
they've been rowing,
you're looking at both
boats for the first time...
A time trial in the
backyard does not count.
That is not the same
thing as a race.
Look at the competition times.
It's not that easy.
Come on, you know that.
Yes. Yes.
Yes, I know.
You're acting like the
varsity boat is scrappin'.
You know that boat hasn't
lost a race either.
And it wasn't that long ago
you were just hopin' the JV boat
was gonna make it to the
finish line without sinking.
Now, Al,
now you're talkin' about
putting all our chips on 'em.
Do you think varsity
could medal in Berlin?
We're not talkin' about a medal.
We're talkin' about a
shot at gettin' there.
If they got there?
I don't know.
We need a win this year, Al.
The people who pay
us, they need a win.
You send a boat full
of kids down there
and they trip up,
you're sticking your
neck way out there.
Makes it a real easy
target. And mine, too.
I need this job.
What do you think, George?
Hmm.
When you were in a boat,
you rowed like no one else
that's ever come through here.
I remember watching you,
wondering how fast one
of my shells could go
if there were eight
just like you in it.
That bunch of kids
might be as close to
that as I'll ever get.
And if I send them out
there and they aren't ready?
Then it's like Tom said.
The axe will likely fall,
and fall hard.
Now you're starting
to sound like my wife.
Well, Hazel's a smart woman.
I'll take that as a compliment.
(CHEERING)
Good morning, everybody.
Thank you.
Now, as we all know, uh,
the Poughkeepsie Regatta
is always the most important
race of the season.
- (SHOUTS OF ASSENT)
- (CHEERING)
This year, there's
even more riding on it,
because the winner will
qualify for an Olympic spot.
- (WILD CHEERING)
- Yes!
It's also a race that the
University of Washington
has not won in
almost two decades,
- but... but...
- (CROWD MURMURS)
we have a boat this year
that I believe could
change all that.
(CHEERING)
A boat that could not
only win at Poughkeepsie,
but
is strong enough to have
a real shot in Berlin.
(WILD CHEERING)
And, uh...
that boat is our junior boat.
- (SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
- (GASPS OF AMAZEMENT)
Yeah, you heard me.
- (LAUGHS)
- (JOYCE WHOOPS)
Listen, I understand
that that's unorthodox.
- Unorthodox? It's insane.
- I'm doing everything I can...
You can't do that.
In the best
interests of our team
and the University
of Washington.
- Thank you.
- (MURMURS OF ASTONISHMENT)
BO BILLINGS: This is bullshit!
- (CLAMORING)
- (CHEERING)
Have you lost your mind?
What about those boys who spent
the last four years
working for this?
- My job is to put the best boat in the water, Ben.
- Your job? I pay for your job.
Without the boosters,
where do you think
the money for your
boats comes from, huh?
For your goddamn salary?
How about you let me do my job?
JAY: Let's just settle down
and talk about this
calmly. Come on.
There's nothin' to
talk about, Jay.
My team, my decision.
Then it's not your team anymore.
I'll make sure your ass is fired
before the train leaves
for Poughkeepsie.
- Ben, we're not gonna get...
- All right.
Bolles is just as
capable as you.
Better even.
I'd do the same as Al.
I hope you know
what you're doing.
Ben!
ULBRICKSON: Do I?
BOLLES: Sure you do.
I can't believe you're
going to the Olympics.
We gotta beat those
other schools first,
but Coach says we have as
good a shot as anybody.
(LAUGHS)
You can't flirt with any
of those New York girls.
(JOYCE GIGGLES)
What's wrong?
Be back in a second.
Joe?
(GRUNTS)
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
Saw your picture in the paper.
Harry Junior clipped it out.
When did you get
back from California?
Couple of years.
You know, things weren't
much better down there.
So, you've been
here all that time?
Down the road a bit.
Were you ever gonna tell me?
You're doin' all right.
I was 14 when you left.
I went to war when
I was that age.
So, what do you wanna do, Joe?
Huh?
Move home?
I mean, I could use the help.
Tell you what, I'll
pay you a dollar a day
if you still remember
how to cut a tree.
Or maybe you'd rather just
keep rowing your boat.
You don't owe me a thing, Joe.
I don't owe you.
You're doing just fine.
I'll pass on regards.
(PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(TRUCK DOOR SHUTS,
ENGINE STARTS)
(PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES)
I'm sorry.
Works out for the best.
Yeah, but that
doesn't make it okay.
Maybe.
I gotta go.
You should come get some sleep
before the sun rises over that.
I'll be in there soon.
I sure love that view.
I know.
I just wish I could enjoy
it the way I used to.
Why don't you
come see if there's
another view you can enjoy?
Okay.
(WISTFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(PLAYING CHEERFUL MUSIC)
(CHEERING AND CLAMORING)
Thank you.
We're gonna be the fastest
crew the world has ever seen.
Bring home the championship, Al!
- And a gold medal!
- We'll try.
Oh, boy.
We might wanna try and
win this thing, huh?
No pressure.
- GIRL: Good luck!
- Bring it home, boys!
I'll be listening on the radio.
Say hello if they interview you.
This might be a good
time to tell you
that I'm in love with you, Joe.
- ANNOUNCER: All aboard!
- All right. I gotta go.
ROGER: Hey! Hey!
HUNT: Yeah, she looked at me.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
(SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
Rantz!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
DAY: I'm busted.
Someone give me a penny.
Lucky, I'll let you watch.
Hey, Joe, give me your jacket.
That'll get me halfway to ante.
Joe, stick around.
DAY: Hey, don't
run away, Hobo Joe.
(CLAMORING)
ROGER: He's playin'.
He's playin'. He's playin'.
He's playin'.
- Jesus, Chuck.
- Was just jokin'.
Yeah, well, your
jokes are lousy.
(SIGHS)
(WISTFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
I didn't mean anything by it.
Truth is, my old man went
bust years ago, so...
Any new clothes I wear,
I swipe from Woolworth's.
Doesn't matter.
Just sayin' we're not different.
You and me.
Except you're not a thief.
(ROUSING MUSIC PLAYING)
One! Way-nuff!
Drop it.
Again! Need to get sharper.
Come on.
You guys are out
of sync. Find Hume.
Take it off Hume.
Look like a team, fellas.
As one.
You're out of sync.
Okay, no, no. Way-nuff.
- Where are we off?
- BOBBY: Hey, Joe, you with us?
- Me?
- Yeah, lock in on Don.
What are you talkin'
about? I'm not the problem.
(HUNT GRUNTS)
ULBRICKSON: Go again.
Come on.
BOBBY: In and through.
In and through.
All right, give me
three more. Three,
two,
one. Way-nuff!
That'd get us a solid sixth.
It's new water, they're
still getting comfortable.
First times were faster. They're
getting less comfortable.
What is the matter?
Not in tune yet. I'll
get 'em there, Coach.
Let's do it before
the race, Bobby.
Go again.
BOBBY: All right, fellas.
Port side, back it down.
Starboard, tap on. Ready?
HAZEL: Probably nervous.
They're just kids, Al.
ULBRICKSON: That's
why everybody told me
I was wrong for bringin' them.
I just can't afford
for them to be kids.
Not anymore.
(ROUSING MUSIC RESUMES)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
(WATCHES CLICK)
- It looks like they...
- I know what's wrong.
Bring it in.
You have 500 perfect meters.
And then another five,
where it looks like
you're rowing eight
different boats.
BOBBY: The timing's
just a little off.
Joe, where is your head at, son?
- It's in the boat.
- No, it's not.
You're setting your own pace.
Your catch is higher
than the rest.
- I'm trying to...
- Don't interrupt me.
You're rowing like
you're in a single.
We've been doing this too
goddamn long to forget
you're in an eight-man shell.
Now, do you wanna be in the boat
or am I'm gonna put
someone else in your seat?
I don't care.
Coy!
You're in Rantz's seat.
Get out. You don't
care? Get out.
Coy, come on, let's go.
Looks like you're
racin' tomorrow.
(OAR RATTLES)
Now, maybe we can row as a team.
And just go talk to Coach,
tell him you want back in.
I'm not beggin' him
to give my place back.
- I'm done with that.
- Where you gonna go?
Ain't like you got money
enough for a train ticket.
I'll figure somethin'
out. I always have.
Are you gonna live in a car in
Poughkeepsie? (KNOCKS SOFTLY)
Hello, Roger. Hello, Joe.
I need to put another
coat on the Husky Clipper.
I could use a hand.
My grandfather would let me
help oil the shells he built.
Most hate it because
of the smell.
I catch the scent of whale oil
and immediately hear his voice
telling me to,
"Keep putting it on
"until you can see your
freckles in the reflection."
That's how I'd know
it was good and slick.
So it would cut through the
water like a knife blade.
How it didn't matter
how fast someone rowed
if the water didn't
flow across the hull
in the exact right way.
If the weight wasn't
balanced just right.
Every piece working
with the other.
It's the same with the crew.
So much that there's really
no difference between the two.
They're connected by all
the hours spent together.
Sweat and pain
bleeds into the grain as
they become one magical thing
that moves across the water
like it was born
to be nowhere else.
I've built a lot of good
boats, but the best ones,
the boats where
every part fits
exactly as it should,
where every man
trusts the one behind him,
they are the boats
people remember forever.
That's what this boat could be.
Be a shame for anyone to miss
seeing how fast it could go
with all the right pieces.
Joe, your dad gave up
on you. He quit on you.
All you know is quitting.
But it seems to
me you're not him.
Or are you?
(LIVELY JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHTER AND CHATTER)
- Yes.
- Yes, it's very nice.
If I can get you two
to just stand together.
Just for one. And perfect.
I'll, uh, see you over there.
What can I do for you, Joe?
I want my seat back.
Why?
All that time I spent in it,
the work we all did together...
(EXHALES) That boat...
it's all I got.
The boys and...
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
It's all I got.
I can't lose that.
You know, one of the first
things I said to you boys was
there's no shame if your
body can't hold up to this.
The same goes for the mind.
Listen, I know it isn't easy
to trust every other person
on that boat as much
as you trust yourself.
But it's not about you.
As good as you are,
it's not about you, Joe,
or me, or anybody else.
It's about the boat.
Yes, sir.
It's where I wanna be.
Okay.
Well, you better get dressed.
Thank you.
Really, thank you.
ROYAL: Today's regatta
is as much a social
experiment as it is a race.
A clash of character.
Of old money versus
no money at all.
Six boats of want-to's against
one filled with have-to's.
These nine working-class boys
arrived from the American West
on the shoulders of a
country that sees itself
in their determined young faces.
Sees their struggles,
their grit, their spirit.
And they've claimed the
Husky Clipper as their own.
Because it's a boat
full of underdogs
representing an underdog nation.
A nation of people who
have been beaten down
but refuse to go away.
Refuse to stop working hard,
'cause that's all they know.
All they have ever done.
So, find your place, by
the river or the radio.
And cheer for guts
and heart and brawn
to beat privilege and prestige
to the finish line today.
Cheer for the boys
from Washington.
(ROUSING MUSIC PLAYING)
Listen up. We're
in lane seven.
Navy and Cal are gonna
wanna jump to a lead.
We just let 'em.
This is it, boys.
Nice, strong start.
We're gonna keep a 42
count coming out, right?
California's gonna
go out hard, okay?
You gotta stick with them.
As long as you're
within two lengths,
- stay under a 30 stroke.
- How's your shoulder?
- Are you okay?
- I'm good.
I wanna see you push
yourself through that pain.
Then go to a 35 at
the halfway mark.
You're gonna slow down and
ease into a nice, steady 34.
Keep going, keep pushing.
Keep pushing all
the way through.
All the boats out in front will start to
tire and you'll just be getting started.
You know the plan.
We'll save something
for the end.
Four miles in a boat
should be nothing to you.
This is your race, all right?
This is our time.
We know what we're doin'.
We've been here before, boys.
Now better get out there and
show 'em what I already know.
(ROUSING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(BOAT WHISTLE BLOWS)
ROYAL: The
Poughkeepsie Regatta.
Today's regatta is the greatest
one-day rowing event in America.
- Watch your step.
- Coaches like Ky Ebright,
Rusty Callow and Al Ulbrickson
are not only hoping for a win,
but a chance to
compete in Berlin.
As rowing fans board
observation cars
and crowd the shores
of the Hudson River,
seven shells take their
places at the starting line.
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- Syracuse, Navy,
Cornell, and Columbia,
Penn, Cal, and Washington
ready themselves
for what could be the
most important race
of their young lives.
A chance to compete
in the Olympics.
(ROUSING MUSIC CONTINUES)
Let's go.
- Good luck, Jack.
- You, too.
(EXHALES)
ROYAL: The starting gun is up.
- Oars to frontstops.
- (ROUSING MUSIC FADES)
Nearly 100,000 spectators hold
their breath in anticipation.
A hush falling over Crum Elbow.
(GUN FIRES)
- Row!
- ROYAL: And here we go.
Washington Huskies
are now rowing
against the seniors of Cal.
Huskies are the only junior
boat in the competition.
Give me a nice, easy 28.
Fall in with Don.
In and through.
ROYAL: These seven
finely trained crews
are churning the waters
of the Upper Hudson
in a supreme rowing test
of power, speed
and coordination.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Hold that pace, Bobby.
And at the quarter mark,
we have California, Penn
and Navy out in front
with a half-boat lead on
the rest of the field.
BOBBY: All right, your
stroke rate is perfect.
Save your power.
Let 'em get tired.
Wear 'em down.
ROYAL: Washington is
falling back to last place.
Four lengths behind the leaders.
Now, Bobby.
Save!
Save power.
Wear 'em down.
- What's he doing?
- It has to be now.
Come on, boys.
BOBBY: Wait for it.
Wait for it.
All right, Don,
give me 36. Go!
Legs through.
ROYAL: And here they come.
Looking for freshwater,
Bobby Moch is steering
right into Syracuse's lane.
- In and through.
- SYRACUSE COXSWAIN: Let's go.
Legs up.
Jab! Jab!
Get off us!
Hey, go to hell, Syracuse!
SYRACUSE COXSWAIN:
What the hell is that?
ROYAL: Washington
is passing Syracuse.
And with a mile and
a half behind them,
teams are falling away
but no one is gaining
on California and Navy.
Attaboy.
Row! Row!
ROYAL: Holding a
four-length lead,
Cal and Navy are
in a two-boat race.
All right, give me 10 big
ones for Ulbrickson. Go!
ROYAL: Washington has
picked up the pace.
Bobby Moch finally getting
his crew in this race.
The Huskies sweeping by Cornell.
Headed for Penn and Columbia.
Navy and Cal still
ahead by four lengths.
BOBBY: All right! Give me 40!
Let's go!
In, through!
ROYAL: Washington is quickly
gaining on Columbia's Lions.
Better not be too late.
ROYAL: The Husky Clipper
bustles by Columbia...
- Come on!
- And into third place!
Come on!
Push! Extend!
Now, give me 10 more
for Pocock!
ROYAL: With 400 meters to
go, here comes Washington!
In and through!
In, through!
- Through!
- Twenty more strokes!
Nineteen!
(ALL GRUNTING)
ROYAL: Washington has
taken second place!
Do they have enough
left to catch Cal?
Legs through!
- GEORGE: Come on, boys.
- Come on.
You got this, boys.
Look at Washington!
I don't believe what I'm seeing.
Can the Huskies do
it? Can they do it?
Give me 10 big ones
for all the people who
didn't believe in you!
Go!
Give me Cal!
I want Cal!
Yeah, we're workin'! Whoo!
MAN: They're
making their move!
MAN 2: Boys, come on.
BOBBY: Legs through!
(SHOUTS OF ENCOURAGEMENT)
ROYAL: With 200 meters left,
Washington is passing Cal!
In, through!
Eyes up!
With 100 meters to go,
Washington is going to do it!
BOBBY: Through!
In and through!
- Eyes up! In!
- Come on.
(WILD CHEERING)
(YELLING)
ROYAL: Washington has
won the race, folks!
Washington has won the race!
(LAUGHS)
- Washington has won!
- (ALL SQUEALING)
What a race!
Coach Ulbrickson's big
gamble has paid off,
ladies and gentlemen.
The Washington Huskies
are going to Berlin
to compete for gold.
- What a race indeed!
- Yes!
Oh...
I do love your smile.
You should do it more often.
(CREW CHEERING)
We did it, boys!
I think that you were trying
to give us all a heart attack.
I just didn't want to break
their rhythm till I had to.
I honest to God didn't know
there were this many
shrimp in the entire world.
Do you mind sharing
with our listeners,
what was the feeling in the boat
when you were four lengths back?
Was there any panic?
Uh, there was no panic.
All of us,
we knew we could make up the
ground when we needed to.
And, if I could,
could I say hello to my
girl Joyce back home?
I'll let you wear the gold
medal when I get back.
ROYAL: That's right, folks.
They'll be bringing
the gold medal home
for all of us back
in Washington.
JOYCE: Oh.
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- ULBRICKSON: This is great.
So, you guys all
knew about it when?
And I'm hearing
about it tonight?
You know what this
sounds like to me?
It sounds like you guys
are changing the rules
because you're trying
to steal this from us.
No one is trying to steal
anything, Coach Ulbrickson.
I'm just speaking to you
as the U.S. Rowing
Olympic Chairman
and telling you the facts.
U.S. Rowing does
not have the money
to fund your trip to Berlin.
And how is that even possible?
It's not just rowing.
Swimming, fencing.
There are many other sports
that are dealing with...
Exactly how much are we
supposed to come up with?
(SIGHS)
- $5,000.
- Five?
- In a week?
- In a week.
And what if we can't
come up with it?
Well, the committee
would have to find
a suitable replacement
to compete in Berlin.
Suitable like who, Henry?
Like your Penn squad?
If necessary, yes.
We'd of course give California
the first opportunity.
Either team is a better option
than not sending a team at all.
This is bullshit,
Henry. It's bullshit.
You didn't expect us
to win, and we won.
Yeah, you couldn't win on
the water. None of you.
I don't like this situation.
Now, you're makin' up
the rules. Bullshit.
HENRY: I don't
like the situation
- any more than you do.
- Yeah, sure you don't.
- Bullshit.
- We'll figure this out.
How are we supposed to
come up with $5,000?
Our university will reach
out to alumni and boosters.
See if they can
scrape anything up.
And if they can't find enough?
Then it'd be Cal
or Penn.
ROGER: We beat those guys.
ULBRICKSON: I know.
BOBBY: No way we let those
rich pricks go instead of us.
Then we better find some money.
(SIGHS) Yeah.
Al, where you goin'?
(LIVELY JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
BOBBY: Help us get to Berlin.
HUNT: Help send the
Huskies to Berlin.
Thank you. You
have a nice day.
- Thank you, sir.
- Sure.
Hey, guys.
The Olympic rowing team needs your help to
get to Berlin. We only got a couple days left.
Fellas, I got a dollar.
Spare a couple dollars.
Help us beat the Germans.
All right.
Thanks. My name's Roger.
Hey, I'm Chuck.
WOMAN: Oh, please.
RADIO ANNOUNCER: Well, you're
running out of days, Coach.
- You have what, four left?
- Three.
And we've only gotten halfway
to what the Olympic
Committee says we need.
RADIO ANNOUNCER: So, if
you don't raise the money,
you go back to Seattle
while some other
team goes to Berlin?
ULBRICKSON: Correct.
And that goes against
everything sports
should be about.
Athletes should be
rewarded for performance.
No politics,
no adjusted scoring or selection
based on wealth and standing.
May the best man win.
That's what they say.
That's what it should be.
These boys, Washington's boys,
this country's boys,
my boys,
they have proven
themselves to be the best.
WOMAN: Help us send
the Huskies to Berlin.
A reminder, folks,
every little bit helps.
Thank you so much.
WOMAN 2: Come on,
support our boys.
All right. Thank you so much.
Thank you so
much. (INDISTINCT)
Thank you so much. Thank you.
(LIVELY JAZZ MUSIC CONTINUES)
We got $92 from Tacoma
in honor of Roger Morris.
$75 more from Sequim
for Joe Rantz.
$90 from Olympia for Don Hume.
Every hometown of these
boys has given somethin'.
Pacific Telegraph just
sent $250 this evening.
BOLLES: Where does that put us
with everything else we've got?
- JAY: Eh, close.
- But?
Well, close is just close, Al.
And we're out of time.
- (EXHALES)
- BOLLES: (SOFTLY) Come on.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Mrs. Ulbrickson, I'm
looking for your husband.
We still got four hours, Ky.
(CHUCKLES) Racing
the clock as usual.
I can't lie to you, Al.
My boys would love
to go to Berlin.
How short are you?
JAY: $300.
Give or take.
EBRIGHT: Hmm.
May I?
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
This is from the Cal Bears.
An IOU for $300.
Give or take.
(EXHALES)
ULBRICKSON: Ky.
(ULBRICKSON EXHALES)
No one deserves to
go but your boys.
Gentlemen.
Mrs. Ulbrickson.
And if there's any extra, you
can bring me back a souvenir.
(LIGHT LAUGHTER)
(MUSIC RISING)
(LAUGHTER)
NEWS ANNOUNCER: Aboard
the SS Manhattan,
a shipload of American
athletes sails for Hamburg.
The Olympic Games, their goal.
Here is Jesse Owens,
the one-man track team from
the University of Ohio.
Some say, "The greatest ever."
More than 300 athletes
will march ashore
on German soil, ready
to fight for gold.
Among the participants are
the University of Washington's
junior varsity
eight-man rowing crew.
The boat is ready to do battle
with the likes of
Italy, Great Britain
and Germany,
all favorites in this
most grueling of events.
In Berlin, the preparations
for the Games are complete,
and the German people
are ready to welcome
athletes from 52 countries.
German Chancellor Adolf Hitler
has promised a
spectacle like no other,
and plans to attend
a variety of events.
In Hamburg, thousands
of cheering Germans
welcome the Americans as
they ready to disembark.
These amateur athletes
have sacrificed so much to
represent their country,
and as the opening of the
Games is just days away,
Americans at home and abroad
look forward to rooting for
these dedicated athletes.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(CROWD WHOOPING)
(MAN GREETS IN GERMAN)
- (GREETING IN GERMAN)
- Hi.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
HUNT: All right.
Get changed, we'll go
look over the course.
This is great.
Not bad.
- This'll do.
- It's better than back home.
GERMAN CREW: Heil Hitler.
Remember the Alamo.
Joe, opening ceremony.
Come on, you're gonna be late.
I think I gotta skip.
I'm just too tired.
Why, what's the problem, Don?
Don doesn't feel so great.
Go join the rest.
I'll, uh... I'll stay.
I'll hang back. You need
to walk with your team.
Thanks, George.
All right, get some rest.
Try and eat somethin'.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(FANFARE PLAYING)
ANNOUNCER: Ungarn.
You're Jesse,
right? Jesse Owens?
I am.
You really the fastest
man in the world?
- I don't know.
- Folks around here say
you're gonna win
every race you're in.
Well, I hope so. (CHUCKLES)
Show those Germans
what for, all right?
- JESSE: No.
- No?
Not the Germans.
The folks back home.
ANNOUNCER: United
States of America.
(CROWD CHEERING)
RADIO ANNOUNCER:
The Hungarian team
offering their respect
to the German leader.
- And here come the Americans.
- (CROWD CHEERING)
With no salute from
the United States.
Sounds like the boys
are making friends.
(ROUSING MUSIC PLAYING)
ULBRICKSON: All right,
the winds are up.
That's good for us. You're
protected in lane two.
Let all the other
boats farther out
deal with the gusts.
Bobby, the tighter
you hold the line,
the smoother the ride.
Now, three prelims.
The winner of each gets an
automatic berth in the finals.
That is what you want.
You want a day off
and let the other teams
wear themselves out
with an extra race.
So, do not hold back.
Great Britain's the team
to watch in our heat.
Bobby, not another Poughkeepsie.
They won't fade like Cal,
so never let them get
more than two lengths up.
ULBRICKSON: Fellas,
you've earned this.
They don't give gold
medals for style.
All that matters is how
fast you are on the water.
And nobody here is faster.
(STARTER SHOUTS IN FRENCH)
(COXSWAIN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
BOBBY: Legs through!
RADIO ANNOUNCER 1: And the
Americans are already leading
by half a boat
over Great Britain
and looking for more.
Followed by France
and Czechoslovakia.
(RADIO ANNOUNCER
2 SPEAKING FRENCH)
BOBBY: In, through!
In, through!
RADIO ANNOUNCER 3:
Stroke Ran Laurie
is digging furiously
for the British boat.
But the Americans
are pouring it on now,
extending their lead.
BOBBY: Eyes up. In, through!
And through!
RADIO ANNOUNCER 1: And
with only 100 meters to go,
the Americans could be closing
in on an Olympic record.
Eyes up!
RADIO ANNOUNCER 1: Six
minutes point eight seconds.
A new Olympic record!
The United States has won!
(CHEERING)
You all right? Hey,
you know we won?
- BOBBY: Don, are you okay?
- You know we won, right? Huh?
- BOBBY: Hey.
- Come on. Come on.
ULBRICKSON: Good race.
Olympic record's a nice start.
But all that does is get us
into the race that matters.
Nobody is gonna remember you
set a record at a preliminary.
Now...
let's go see what
we're up against.
Good job.
BOLLES: Way to go. Way to go.
ULBRICKSON: Good work, boys.
(COXSWAIN DIRECTING IN GERMAN)
Singles, doubles,
fours, they haven't
lost a race yet.
(COXSWAIN DIRECTING IN GERMAN)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Fast.
Don, come on.
Hey, come on.
You all right?
Coach! Coach!
- You okay?
- Mm-hmm. I'm just worn out.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thanks for your help.
What's the word?
Some kind of bug.
They're not sure what.
Right now, he's very dehydrated.
He needs rest.
And y'all stay away from
him for the next 24 hours.
We can't afford
losing anybody else.
What do you mean, "losing"?
If he's still like this in
two days, he's not racing.
Lane assignments for the finals.
ULBRICKSON: You can't
change the rules
in the middle of a competition!
The fastest qualifiers
earn the favored lanes.
That is the way
it's always been.
And we posted the best time,
and you've gone and
stuck us on the outside.
This was the lane formula
the committee decided on.
When? Right after your squad
posted the slowest
qualifying time?
Be careful of your
accusations, Coach Ulbrickson.
You've seen the winds on
that course and you know
there's a two-length
disadvantage when it blows.
I'm sure your crew will manage.
The forecasters
expect a calm day.
Well...
We'll protest this.
Noted. And good luck.
(SOLEMN MUSIC PLAYING)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
(SOLEMN MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING GERMAN)
ULBRICKSON: All right.
Listen up, boys.
It's a tough lane, so
you gotta start quick.
You gotta keep them in sight.
That wind will be blocked
for the last 500 meters.
And that's your shot.
That's where you're
gonna take 'em,
but only if you
keep 'em in sight.
Listen, every one of those teams
have trained their whole
lives for this moment.
They're all legacies.
We're not.
Row for your country.
Row for each other.
Row for that one
moment when everything
that's stacked against
you can take a back seat.
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
For what it's worth,
I'm proud of you boys.
All right, push off.
What?
Nothin'.
- (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
- (ANNOUNCER SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING ITALIAN)
ROGER: They might as
well have stuck us
out on the North Atlantic.
ANNOUNCER 2: Thousands of
people are taking their seats,
gathered for the
Men's Eights finals.
The world's six
best rowing teams
in one last race for the gold.
Germany, Italy, Hungary.
Germany has taken gold in
singles, doubles, and fours,
and they're looking for a sweep.
Switzerland, Great Britain,
and the United States
round out the six.
The boys from
Washington so close
to bringing an Olympic
title back to Seattle.
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Deutschland! Deutschland!
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
Don, you okay?
- (BREATH SHUDDERS)
- You got this, Don, all right?
(STARTER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, what'd he say?
All right. Come
on, let's win this.
Oars ready.
(COXSWAIN SPEAKS ITALIAN)
Come on.
All right, we got
two lengths of wind
to make up on this bunch.
- (STARTER SHOUTS IN FRENCH)
- So, we start at 38.
Bobby! Bobby!
Shit! Row! Row!
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING GERMAN)
Come on.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, God! He couldn't hear him.
ANNOUNCER 2: The Americans have stumbled
out of the gate, already a full boat behind.
(COXSWAIN DIRECTING
IN HUNGARIAN)
Legs through.
All right, now move to 30.
Go! In, through.
Legs through!
In, through! In!
(COXSWAIN SHOUTS IN HUNGARIAN)
(COXSWAIN SHOUTS IN ITALIAN)
BOBBY: All right. We got 38!
Give me 40!
In, through!
In, through! Go!
Come on, Don, pick it up.
In the legs! In, through!
In, through!
- In, through!
- It's time to move!
Come on, Don.
Go, Don!
Come on, boys.
(SPEAKS GERMAN)
(COXSWAIN DIRECTING IN GERMAN)
(DIRECTING IN ITALIAN)
(SHOUTS OF ENCOURAGEMENT)
ANNOUNCER 2: Germany
is just behind Italy,
followed by Great Britain.
The U.S. still in last,
well behind Hungary.
Give me more! Gotta have more!
(VOICE CRACKING) Come
on, Don. Give me 40.
In the legs.
- Push it, Don.
- BOBBY: Come on, Don!
Now would be a good time, Hume!
Come on, Don! Pick it up!
Don, come on.
Come on, Don.
Gotta give me 40. You have it.
Give it to me.
Come on, give me 40.
Come on, Don.
Come on!
Don!
Don! Come on!
(SINGING) Every
morning, every evening
Ain't we got fun?
Not much money, oh, but honey
Ain't we got...
That's right, Don! Give me 40!
Go! Through!
- Legs through!
- (HUME BREATHING HEAVILY)
Eyes up!
Stay low!
- Stay loose!
- ANNOUNCER 2: And here comes
the United States with a burst.
BOBBY: Row!
As one!
(COXSWAIN SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
ANNOUNCER 2: Nearing
the 500-meter mark,
the Americans have caught up
to the Hungarian
and Swiss teams.
Stay!
(COXSWAIN SHOUTING
IN HUNGARIAN)
And through! In, through!
ANNOUNCER 2: The
Americans have overtaken
the Swiss and the
Hungarian boats.
Germany and Italy
share the lead,
with Great Britain trailing.
BOBBY: Legs loose!
In, through!
In and through!
COXSWAIN: Four! Five!
BOBBY: In, through!
Give me 42!
Now!
In, through!
Breathe!
- Legs through!
- BOBBY: In, through!
Fifteen more! In!
- Come on.
- BOBBY: Through!
Ten more!
Shoulders down and loose.
Stand tall!
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
In, through!
ANNOUNCER 2: And the
Americans continue strong,
moving past Great Britain
and headed for third.
The U.S. is moving
into medal position.
Through! Eyes up!
(DIRECTING IN GERMAN)
In, through!
(COXSWAIN SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
(SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
(SHOUTING LOUDER)
(GRUNTING HEAVILY)
Give me 46!
Go!
ANNOUNCER 2: 300 meters,
and the Americans
have pulled even!
The boats are three across
now. 250 meters to go.
- (MOUTHING) Come on, come on, come on.
- Legs through!
ANNOUNCER 2: It's
a three-boat race.
Who's going to break?
(SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
It's Germany, Italy.
Italy, Germany.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
The U.S. and Italy.
It's just too close.
BOBBY: Stay low!
ANNOUNCER 2: 100 meters to go.
It's neck and neck.
(EXCITED CHEERING)
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
Come on.
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Deutschland! Deutschland!
In, through!
(CREW GRUNTING HEAVILY)
Give it everything! Go!
(SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
BOBBY: Stay central!
Eyes up!
(SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
BOBBY: As one!
As one!
Off the man in front of you!
In, through!
Go! In, through!
Eyes up!
In the legs!
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Deutschland! Deutschland!
ANNOUNCER 2: Germany,
Italy, America.
CROWD: Deutschland!
Deutschland!
-  (CROWD CHEERING)
- ANNOUNCER 2: And that's it!
That's it!
The results are just too close
for this reporter to tell.
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Come on.
(ALL PANTING EXHAUSTEDLY)
Who won?
ANNOUNCER 2: The
German fans believe
they've got their sixth
win of these 1936 Olympics.
We can only sit and
wait for the results.
Did you see?
(UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES)
- America.
- (CROWD CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER 2: The United
States has won the gold!
(WILD CHEERING)
(SLOW TRIUMPHANT
MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHTER)
JOE: Good job, Johnny.
ROGER: We did it, boys!
MCMILLIN: Come on!
- JOE: One hell of a stroke.
- (LAUGHTER)
(SNIFFLES)
(EXHALES)
(CHUCKLING)
(ALL CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER 2:
America has done it!
- They've won the gold!
- (LAUGHING)
- (LAUGHTER)
- Hell of a race.
- You did it, Al. You did it.
- I'm proud of you.
We did it.
(CROWD CHEERING)
ROYAL: How about this, huh?
ULBRICKSON: Mm-hmm.
How about this?
Anything you'd like to
say about those boys, Al?
They are the finest I ever
saw seated in a shell.
(SLOW TRIUMPHANT
MUSIC CONTINUES)
Not bad, huh, fellas?
(LAUGHTER)
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(BOY GRUNTING)
Did you see that?
Boat pushed me
right into the bank.
- Look at this.
- Don't worry, we'll fix it.
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, Grandpa?
You think someday
I can row crew?
Well, you gotta keep at it.
Did you like rowing
eight-man crew?
- Eight?
- Yeah.
We were never eight.
We were one.
(CHUCKLES QUIETLY)
(GENTLE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)