Do you ever look at someone and wonder...
what is going on inside their head?
well I know.
I know Rylie's head
And there she was
Hello
Rylie
Oh look at you, aren't you a little bundle of joy
Aren't you a little bundle of joy?
It was amazing, just Rylie and me ... forever
Oh for 33 seconds...
I am Sadness. Oh hello .. I am Joy
Can I just ... If you could ... I just wanna fix that ... Thanks.
And that was just the beginning.
Headquarter's only got more crowded from there.
Very nice, looks like you got this .. very good
Ohhh look out! That's fear ... he's really good at keeping Rylie safe.
easy easy .. Ha! pop back!! Oh we are good. Thank you, thank you very much.
and we are back
Here we go, alright ... open
Mmmmm, this looks new ... Do you think it's safe? What is it?
Okay caution, there is a dangerous smell people. Oh hold on what is that?
This is disgust, she basically keeps Rylie from being poisoned
physically and socially ... That is not redly coloured or shaped like a denis .. Hold on guys, it's broccoli!
Yuckii!!
well I just saved our lives. Yeah you are welcome.
Rylie if you don't eat your dinner, you are not gonna get any desert
Wait! did he just say we couldn't have desert?!
That's anger, he cares very deeply about things beig fair.
So that's how you wanna play it old man?! No desert!
Oh sure, we will eat our dinner right after you eat this!
Ahhhhhhhhhh!!
Rylie Rylie ... here comes the airplane ... Ouuhhh!
Oh airplane, we got an airplane everyody. Ohhhh!
And you've met Sadness, she .. well she ..
I am not actually sure what she does.
and I've checked, there is no place for her to go so she is good, we are good, it's all great.
anyway these are Rylie's memories and they are mostly happy you'll notice ... not to brag
but the really important ones are over here. I don't wanna get too technical but these are
called core memories, each one came from a super important time in Rylie's life
like when she first scored a goal, it was so amazing
would you look at that? very nice.
Woahhhhhh !!
and each core memorie powers a different aspect of Rylie's personality.
like Hockey island ...
goofball island is my persoanl favourite.
hahahaha! come back here you little monckey.
Yup goofball is the best.
friendship island is pretty good too.
ohhhh I love honesty island and that's the truth.
and of course family island is amazing.
the point is the islands of personality are what make Rylie Rylie.
Lavaaa ... Wohooouuh !
Who is your friend who rides a bike? Bing Bong Bing Bong
Ahhhh! Brain freeze!
Yeahhh! yayyyy
Good night kiddo.
Good night dad.
and ... we are out.
that's what i am talking about. Ohhh! Another perfect day.
Nice job everybody. Let's get those memories down to longterm.
Alright! we knoked it out today, I am gonna call that success.
and that's it, we love our girl.
she's got great friends, she's got a great house.
Things couldn't be better.
After all Rylie is 11 now, what could happen?!
What!! Ahhhh!
Okay. Not what I had in mind.
Ahhhhh!
Hey look the golden gate bridge. Isn't that great?!
It's not made out of solid gold like we thought which is kinda disapointment but still.
A shrin belady told me earthquakes are a myth joy. Otherwise I will be terrified right now.
Ahhhh yeah.
these are my kind of people.
Alright just a few more blocks. we're almost to our new house.
step on it daddy! why don't we just live in a smelly car?!
We've already been in it forever!
which actually was really lucky because that gave us plenty of time to think
about what our new house is going to look like.
Whattt! Let's review the top ideal dreams.
Ohhh that looks safe.
that looks nice.
Ohhh! that would be great for Rylie.
Oh! No no no this. Joy for the last time she cannot live in a cookie.
That's the one, it comes with a dragon.
We are getting close, I can feel it.
This, this i our new house. Annnnd ...
Maybe it's nice on the inside.
we are supposed to live here?!
we have to .. I am telling you it smells like something died in here!
Could you die from moving?!
guys you are overreacting, nobody is dy.. A dead mouse!
AHHHHH!
I am gonna be sick. the house of the dead. What are we gonna do?
we are gonna get rebbies.
get of me!
Hey hey hey all through the drive. Dad talked about how cool our new room is.
let's go check it out.
It's gonna be great. Yes yes yes.
Noooo no no no.
I am starting to envy the dead mouse.
get out the rubber ball. We're in a solitary confinment.
Rylie can't live here. He's right. That the worse.
It's really bad. It's absolutely the worse.
Hey it's nothing our butterfly curtains couldn't fix.
I read somewhere that an empty room is an opportunity.
where did you read that?
it doesn't matter. I read it and it's great.
We will put the bed there and the desk over there.
The hockey lamp goes there. We will put the chair there.
stars.. yeah I like that. Now we are talking.
Let's go get our stuff out from the moving van.
Alright goodbye. Well guess what?
the moving van won't be here until thursday.
You are kidding.
the van is what?! Oh yeah. The van is lost.
You said it would be here yusterday.
I know that's what I said. That's what they told me.
We would better stress out! What are we gonna do?
I've got a great idea!
Did you even read the contract?
and then she makes some move, she is closing in.
Hey oh no you are not.
she is running over the grass.
and she scores.
yeahhh!
What grandma! Grandma?!
Oh she put her hair up, we're in for it.
Heyyy, put me down.
Ah sorry hold on, hold on.
Hello! Wait.
You are kidding, Ah stall it for me, I will be right there.
The investors are supposed to show up on thursday not today, I gotta go.
it's okay, we get it. I hope that's for the best, Thank's hon.
See you sweetie.
Dad just left us. Oh he doesn't love us anymore, that's sad.
I should drive, right?
Joy! What are you doing?
Ahhhh just give me one second.
You know what I realized? Rylie hasn't have launch, remember!
Hey I saw  a pizza place down the street .. maybe we could try that.
pizza sounds delecious. Pizza yes pizza.
Let's get it.
What the heck is that?!
Who puts brocolli on pizza?!
that's it. I am done.
Congratulations San Fransisco you've ruined pizza.
Fasta Hawaians and now you.
What kind of a pizza place only serves one kind of pizza?
It must be a San Fransisco thing.
still it's not bad as that soup, that dinner in Nabrasca.
Oh yeah the spoon stood up from the soup by itself.
That's disgusting. Oh good, family is running.
The drive was pretty fun, Ha?
What was your favourite part? Spitting out of the car window.
Definitely not when Dad was singing.
wearing a seatbelt.
Ohh! what about the time with a dinosaur?
Oh that's the one.
say cheese.
Dad dad dad dad the car! Just look behind you.
Noo no no no.
Haha nice one Joy.
I liked that time with a dinosaur.
That was pretty funny.
Wait what?! what happened?
she did something to the memory!
what did you do? I just touched it.
that should make it change. Ohhh change it back Joy.
I am trying. You can't change it back?!
No, I guess I can't. Good going Sadness, now when Rylie thinks of that moment with dad
she is gonna feel sad.
Bravo! I am sorry Joy, I don't really know .. I thought maybe if you .. if I .. I mean ..
Joy we got a stairway coming up.
Just don't touch any other memory until we figure out what is going on.
Okay.
Alright, get ready this is a monster railing and we are riding it all the way down.
wait what! what happened?
A core memory! Oh no!
Sadness what are you doing? it looked like it's almost crooked
so I opened it and then it fell out.
Ohhhhh!
It's just that, I wanted maybe to hold one.
Ohhh Joy! Wow wow wow!
Sadness you nearly touched a core memory and when you touch them we can't change it back.
I know, I am sorry.
something is wrong with me.
it's like I am having a breakdown.
you are not having a breakdown. It's stress.
I keep making mistakes like that.
I am awful. No, you are not. and annoying.
Well, you know what you can't focus on what's going wrong.
there is always a way to turn things around, to find the fun.
yeah, find the fun. I don't know how to do that.
Okay, well try to think of something funny.
Ohhhh remember the funny movie where the dog dies?
Ah yeah, that's not .. What about that time with Meg when Rylie
laughed so hard, milk came out of her nose. Come on.
yeah that hurt, it fel like fire.
Okay let's think about something else, what are your favourite things to do?
my favourite? Well I like it when we are outside.
that's good, like there is the beach and sunshine.
Oh like that time we burried dad in the sand up to his neck.
I was thinking more like rain. Rain.
Rain is my favourite too
we can stumb around in puddles, you know?
There is cool umbrellas, lightining storms.
More like when the rain runs on our back and makes your shoes thuggy and we get all cold and shivery
everything starts feeling drobby. Oh hey hey easy, why are you crying?
it's like really the opposite of what we are going for here.
Crying helps me slow down an obsessive way of life's problems.
you know what, let's think about something else, how about we read some mind manuals?
Ha? sounds fun. I've read most of them.
Well have you read this one? this one seems interesting.
"Longterm memory retrieval volume 47"? No. A real page turner.
Longterm memory data selection via channel subgrouping? see? Fun already.
Oh you lucky dog, you are reading these cool things, I gotta go work
Life is so unfair. Ahhh!
what do we do? We only got half of the last month maybe two.
If we can't find investors by then, we are gonna have to lay people off.
Mom! Dad! Come kiss me goodnight.
Be right there! I know you gotta land this.
Did you hear Dad? He sounded really upset.
What was that? Is it a bear? It's a bear!
There is not bears in San Fransisco.
I saw a really hairy guy, he looked like a bear.
I am so jumpy, my nerves are shut!
Ohhh I don't want to hear about your nerves.
I'll tell you what it is, this move's been a bus.
That's what I have been telling you guys.
There is at least 37 things for Rylie to be scared of right now.
The smell alone is enough to make her gag.
I can't believe mom and dad moved us here!
Look! I get it, you guys have concerns but we have been through worse.
I'll tell you what, let's make a list of all the things Rylie should be happy about.
Fine. Let's see the house stinks, our room stinks
it smells wierd here, our friends are back home.
and all of our stuff are in the missing van.
Oh come on, it could be worse. Yeah Joy, we could be lying on the dirty floor in a bag.
Okay I admit it, we had a rough start but think of all the good things that.. No Joy
there is absolutely no reason for Rylie to be happy right now. Let us handle this.
I say we skip school tomorrow and lock oursleves in the bedroom.
We have no clean clothes, I mean no one should see us
We could cry until we can't breathe.
We should lock the door and say that curse word we know. It's a good one.
Now hold on, look we all have our off days you know?
Hi honey. The mom bad news train is pulling in. Tut tut!
still no moving van, now they're saying it won't be here until Tuesday.
Can you believe it? Tut tut tut!
Where is dad? On the phone, this new van triskie has been relly busy.
I rest my case.
your dad is a little stressed, he is about keeping his campagny up and running.
Now for a few well placed withering scouts.
I guess all I really wanna say is thank you. Ha?
you know, through all this confusion you've stayed, well you've stayed our happy girl.
your dad is under a lot of pressure but if you and I can keep smiling, it would be a big help.
We can do that for him, right?
Wow! well, yeah sure.
What did we do to deserve you?
Sweet dreams.
Good night.
well you can't argue with mom, happy it is.
Sounds great. Totally behind you Joy.
looks like we are going in a rpm. I've got dream duties so I'll take care of sending
these to longterm. Great day today guys.
Alright what's on tonight dream production?
Oh this is it, the new place.
Come live with me Rylie
Somebody ordered a Brocolli pizza?
eat me! I'm organic.
No. Who is in charge of programming down there?
I know I am not supposed to do this but
We are not going to end the day like this.
Don't you worry, I'm gonna make sure that tomorrow is another great day.
I promise.
Hello! Did I wake you?
Do you have to play that? Well I have to practice and I don't think of it as
playing so much as hugging.
Okay first day of school. very very exciting.
I was up late last night figuring out a new plan.
Here it is, fear I need a list of all the possible negative outcomes on the first day at the new school.
Way ahead there, Did anyone notice a film mediore?
Disgust, make sure Rylie stands out today but also blends in.
When I am through, Rylie will look so good
the other kids will look at her own outfit and barf.
Joy! Yes Joy? You will be in charge of the console keeping Rylie
happy all day long and may I say I love your dress.
it's adorable. Oh! this old thing? Thank you so much.
I love the way it rolls.
train of thoughts ... right on schedule.
Anger, unload the day dreams.
I ordered extra in case things get slow in class.
might come in handy if this new school is full of boring useless classes
which it probably will be.
Sadness, I have a super important job just for you.
Really? Hmmmm!
Follow me.
What are you doing?
And there perfect.
this is the circle of sadness.
your job is to make sure that all the sadness stays inside of it.
Sooo you want me to just stand here?
Hey, it's not my place to tell you how to do your job.
Just make sure that allll the sadness stays in the circle
See? You're a pro with this.
Isn't this fun?
No.
I gotta go.
Alright, everyone
fresh start, we are gonna have a good day which will turn into a good
week which will turn into a good year which turns into a good life.
Sooo big day, new school
new friends, Ha?
I know, I am kinda nervous but I am mostly excited
How do I look?
very cute. You are gonna be okay?
Do you want us to walk with you?
Mom and dad with us in public?!
No thank you.
I'm on it. No, I'm fine.
Bye Mom, bye dad.
Have a good day at school monkey.
*Hoo hoo hoo*
Have a great day sweetheart.
Are you sure we wanna do this? In we go.
Okay, going in ... yes.
Okay we gotta a group of cool girls at 2 o'clock.
How do you know? Double ears pairs, infinity scarf.
Wow! is she wearing an eye shadow? We wanna be friends with them.
Oh let's go talk to them.
Are you kidding?! We are not talking to them.
We want them to like us.
Ohhhh! Wait what?
Almost finished with the potential disasters.
scenario is either quick sands, spontaneous combustion
or getting called on by the teacher.
So as long as none of this happens ..
Okay everybody, we have a new student in class today.
Are you kidding me?! Out of the gates, this is not happening!
Rylie, would you like to tell us something about yourself?
Nooooooooo.
pretend we can't speak english.
Don't worry, I got this.
Oh okay, my name is Rylie Anderston.
I'm from Menasota and now I live here.
and how about Menasota? can you tell us something about it?
well you certainly get a lot more snow then we do.
Hahaha! she is so hilarious. Hahaha!
yeah it gets pretty cold. ... is over and tthat's when we play hockey.
I'm on a great team. We're called the perry dogs.
my friend Meg plays forward and my dad's a coach.
Pretty much, everyone in my family skates.
It's kinda of a family tradition, we go out on the lake almost every weekend.
Or we did till I moved away...
What? Hey Sadness!
You touched a memory! We talked about this .
Oh yeah I know, I am sorry.
Get back in your circle!
Oh what's going on?
We used to play tag and stuff...
Did you see that look? They're judging us!
Somebody help me! Grap that.. Everybody put...
but everything is different now since we moved.
Oh no! We are crying at school!
What! Sadness what are you doing?
I'm sorry.
Ah! It's a core memory.
It's blue.
No, wait. Stop it.
No
Joy No! That's a core memory.
Stop it! Let go!
Ahhh! the core memories!
No no no no!
Thank you Rylie, I know it can be tough moving to a new place
but we are happy to have you here.
Alright everyone get out your history books and turn to chapter 7
Can I say that curse word now?
Ahhhhhh!
Oh no! 1 .. 2 .. 3 .. okay
Where are we?
Longterm memory!
Goofball island?!
Rylie's islands of personality, they're all down!
Ohhhh! This is bad
We... we can fix this
We just have to get back to headquarters, plug the core memories in
and Rylie will be back to normal
Ohhh! Rylie has no core memories, no personality islands and no .....
What?! What is it?
You! You are not in headquarters, without you Rylie can't be happy.
We gotta get you back up there.
I'm coming Rylie
So as it turns out, the green trash can is not recycling
it's for greens like combusts and egg shells..
and the blue one is recycling, and the black one ...
Rylie is acting so wierd, why is she acting so wierd?!
What do you expect? All the islands are down
Joy would know what to do
That's it, until she gets back we just do what Joy would do
great idea! Anger .. fear .. disgust .. How are we supposed to be happy?!
Hey Rylie I've got good news .. I found a junior hockey league
right here in San Fransisco and get this
trials are tomorrow after school, what luck right!
Hockey?! Oh oh what do we do?
guys .... you ... you pretend to be Joy
Won't it be great to be back on the ice?
Oh yeah, that sounds fantastic.
What was that?! That wasn't anything like Joy.
Ahhh! because I'm not Joy
yeah, no kidding
Did you guys pick up on that?!
Oh yeah! Something is wrong.
Should we ask her?
Let's probe but keep it settled so she doesn't notice.
So how was the first day of school?
She's probing us...
I'm done, you pretend to be Joy.
Oh okay, Hmmm
It was fine, I guess... I don't know.
Oh very smooth ... that was just like Joy
something is definitely going on..
she never acted like this before
What should we do? We're gonna find out what's happening
but we will need support, signal the husband
Hmmmm...
what a nice bat over the rief...
Hmmmmm...
Oh oh she is looking at us
What did she say?
Sorry sir, no one was listening
is it garbage night?! we left the toilet seat up
What?! what is it woman ... what?!
Ahh .. he's making that stupid face again
I could strangle him right now!
signal him again
Ahhh! so Rylie how was school?
Seriously!! you're kidding me
for this we gave up a brazilian helicopter pilot!
Move I'll be Joy...
School was great, alright?!
Rylie, is everything okay?
Ahhh!
Sir, she just rolled her eyes at us
What is her deal?!
Alright, make a show force
I don't have to put the foot down
No, not the foot!
Rylie, I do not like this new attitude
Oh I'll show you attitude..
No, no no stay happy!
What is your problem?!
Just leave me alone
Sir, reporting high level of sas
take it to deaf cone 2
You heard that gentlemen, deaf cone 2
Listen young lady, I don't know where this
disrespectful attitude came from.
you wanna a piece of this pops?!
Come and get it.
Yeah well ... well
Here it comes, prepare the foot
keys inserted to position
Waiting to launch on your command, sir
Just shut up!
Fire!
That's it, go to your room.
Now!
Foot is down.. The foot is down
Good job, gentlemen.
That could have been a disaster.
Well, that was a disaster.
Come fly with me, Gargenya!
Ahhh!
We're gonna walk out there, on that!
It's the quickest way back.
But it's right over the memory dump, if we fall we'll be forgotten forever!
We have to do this for Rylie, just follow my footsteps.
Oh okay!
It's not that high, it's totally fine.
Ohhhh!
Hey.
So things got a little out of hand down stairs
Don't you want to talk about it?
Come on, where is my happy girl?
Monkey! Woo woo woo...
Oh he's trying to start goofball
Ahhh! go back, go back
What the?!
I get it, you need some alone time.
We'll talk later.
We have a major problem
Oh Joy where are you?!
We lost goofball island, that means she could loose friendship
and hockey and honesty and family...
you can fix this, right Joy?
Ahh! I don't know
Ohhh!
But we have to try.
Okay, come on.
Rylie's gone to sleep...
which is a good thing, when you think about it because nothing else
bad could happen while she's asleep
We'll be back to headquarters before she wakes up.
We'll just go across friendship island
Ohhh! We'll never make it. Ohh!
No no no, don't obsess the way of life problems, remember the funny movie where the dog dies.
Oh Sadness! We don't have time for this.
We'll just have to go around, take the scener crew
Wait Joy you could get lost in there.
Think positive!
Okay, I'm positive you will get lost in there.
That's longterm memory, an endless warn of corners and shelfs
I've read it about it in the manuals.
The manuals?! the manuals, you read the manuals!
Yeah.
So you know the way back to headquarters.
I ... I guess
Ohhhh!
You are my map, let's go
lead on my map.
Show me where we are going.
Okay, only
I'm too sad to walk, just give me a few hours to..
Oh! which way, left?
Right! No I mean go left
I said left was right like correct.
Okay.
This actually feels kinda nice.
Okay here we go, we will back to headquarters before morning.
We can do it, this will be easy.
This is working...
Ahhh! This is not working, are we getting close?
Yeah just another right anddd... a left and then another... left and ...
Ah! Are you sure you know where we're going cause we seem to be walking away from headquarters?!
Rylie is awake.
Oh! Oh ... No no don't touch, remeber? If you touch them they stay sad.
Oh sorry, I won't... starting now.
Ohh! I can't take much more of this.
Forget them!
Mind workers!
But Joy we're almost .. Ohhh!
Phone numbers .. we don't need all of these, they're in her phone
Just forget all of them, please.
Forget them.
I need to find friendship island.
Four years of piano lessons, yeah it looks pretty faded
You know what, save chopsticks and hurt soul and get rid of the rest.
Are you?! US prisoners, what do you think?
Yeah she keeps watching Lincoln in the fab.
Forget them.
Hey, you can't throw these away.
Those are perfectly good memeories.
the names of every cutie pie princess, no.
Yes, that's critical information, glitter storm, honey pence...
Forget them.
Hey, bring those back.
They're in the dump, nothing comes back from the dump.
Yeah, look lady this is our job
when Rylie doesn't care about a memorie, it fades.
Fades?!
It happens to the best of them
Yeah except for this bad boy, hmmm
This one will never fade..
Tripple dent gum... will make you...
The song from the gum commercial?!
You know, sometimes we send that one up to headquarters for no reason.
It just plays in Rylie's head over and over again like a million times.
Let's watch it again.
Triple dent gum, will make you...
We all know this song, okay.
What do you think, shall we do it?
Yeah, ahahaha!
Here we go.
Triple dent gum...
What the?! This again!
Hey, do you know how to get to friendship island?
Triple dent gum... hmmm
Did you like it there?
Did you feel any earthquakes?
Is the brich cool?
Yeah it's good, what happened with the play offs?
We won the first game, cause we actually may go to the finals this year.
Oh and we've got this new girl in the team, she's so cool.
Ahhh! She did not just say that.
A new girl?! Meg has a new friend already!
Ohhh!
Hey hey hey stay happy, we do not want to loose any more islands here guys.
We can pass the pod to each other without even looking, it's like mind reading...
You like to read minds? I got something for you to read...
Ahhhh!
I gotta go. What? I gotta go.
Please tell me which way is ... Oh no!
Friendship island! What?!
Ah, not friendship!
Ohhh Rylie loved that one and now it's gone.
Goodbye friendship, hello loneliness.
We'll just have to go the long way.
Yeah the long long long long way.
I'm ready.
Hmmmm! there's gotta be a better way.
Ohhh look at you.
Ahh! I will take you but not you.
Awww! Who am I kidding, I can't leave you.
Hellooo! Ahhhh!
Wait, hey wait!
Wow wait, stop.
Exuse me? Ahhhh!
Ahh .. I was looking for a ... diversion
What?!
Ahhh! So long, sucker.
Awww! I hurt all over.
Wait, I know you.
No you don't, I get that a lot.
I look like a lot of people. No no no I do.
Ahhh! Bing Bong, Rylie's imaginary friend!
You really do know me?! Well of course, Rylie loves playing with you,
you too are best friends.
Oh, oh you would know
we're trying to get back to headquarters
Headquarters?! Are you guys from headquarters?!
Well, oh yeah I'm Joy, this is Sadness.
You're Joy?! The Joy?!
Hmmm.
What the heck are you doing right here?!
That's a good question, you wanna answer that Sadness?
Ahhh! Without you, Rylie will never be happy.
We can't have that, we gotta get you back
Ah, I'll tell you what, follow me.
Ah, thank you. It is so great to see you again
I gotta tell you, I am such a good fan of your work.
Do you remember when you and Rylie were in a band?
I went to all of your concerts, yeah I blow a mean nose.
Watching you playing tag was such a treat!
Good time, we were all champs.
Oh and remember your rocket?
Of course, it runs on song power.
That's right, your theme song.
Who's your friend who likes to play? Bing Bong Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell horray! Bing Bong Bing Bong
What exactly are you supposed to be?!
You know it's unclear, I'm mostly cotton candy
But shapewise I'm part cat , part elephant, part dolphin.
Dolphin?!
You gotta remember when Rylie was three, animals were all the rage.
The cow goes mow, the horse goes nay .. It's all people talked about that.
Yeah, yeah I guess that's true.
What are you doing out here?
Well that's not much for an imaginary friend lately so ....
You know... Hey hey don't be sad
I'll tell you what when I get back to headquarters I'll make sure Rylie remembers you.
You will? Of course, she would love that.
Ahhhh! This is the greatest day of my life...
Awwww aww! What's going on?
I cry candy, try the caramel, it's delecious.
Ohhh! Ahhh!
Ohhh here use this. Thanks.
Oh hold on, wait a second.
It always get stuck at the bottom..
Here.
What? It's imaginary.
Thanks, this will make it a lot easier to walk back to headquarters.
Walk?! We're not walking.
We're taking the train of thoughts.
The train? Of course, that's so much faster but how do we catch it?
Well it kinda goes all over the place but there is a station in imagination land.
I know a shortcut, come on this way.
Ah I'm so glad we ran into you.
The station is right here.
After you.
Joy! What?
Well I read about this place in the manual, we shouldn't go in there.
Bing Bong says it's the quickest way to headquarters.
No, but Joy this is abstract thoughts.
What are you talking about? I go in here all the time, it's a shortcut you see?
D .. A .. N .. G .. E .. R .. shortcut!
I'll proove it to you.
Look at me I'm close to the station cause I'm taking the shortcut.
Let's go around this way.
Almost there.
If you wanna walk the long way , go for it but Rylie needs to be happy.
I'm not missing that train, BingBong knows what he is doing.
He's part dolphin, they're very smart.
Well I guess.
Okay, what abstract concepts are we trying to comprehend today?
Ahhh, loneliness.
hmmm looks like there is something is in there, I'm gonna turn it on for a minute and
burn out the cank.
What did I tell you, you'll be in headquarters in no time.
Ahhhh! Hey would you look at that?
Oh what's happening? Oh no they turned it on.
I've never seen this before.
My face! My beautiful face
What's going on?! We're abstracting, there are four stages.
This is the first, none objective fragmentation ...
Alright, do not panic. What is important is that we all stay together.
Oh! The second stage, we're deconstructing...
I can't feel my legs. Oh here they are.
Come here me.
We gotta get out of here before we are not even shape and colour.
We'll get stuck here forever.
Why did we come in here?!
I told you it's a shortcut.
The train.
Oh no, we're two dimensional, that's stage three.
We're getting no where.
Depth! I'm lacking depth!
Come on.
We can't fit.
Oh no we're not figuritive!
This is the last stage!
We're not gonna make it.
Wait we're two dimensional, fall on your face.
Stop, stooop!
Noo, you said it was a shortcut.
I did but wow, we should have not got in there, that was dangerous.
They really should put up a sign.
How long till the next train?
Who knows?
But don't worry, there is another station that way.
The train always stops there, right before it goes to headquarters.
If we hurry we can catch it.
This isn't another one of your shortcuts, is it?
Hahahaha, yeah!
is there really another station? Aha, through there.
Welcome to imagination land.
Imagination land?! Sure, I come here all the time, I'm practically the mair.
Hey, are you guys hungry?
There is french fries forest.
No way, hahaha.
Oh oh! Check it out, trophy town.
Medals, ribbons, everyone is a winner.
I won first prize. Me too.
Ohhh, participation award.
Wait is that?! Look, it's cloud town.
Ahhhh that's my favourite.
Ohhh, it's so soft.
Ohhh let me try.
Hey what's the big idea? You better fix that wall or else you're in a big trouble...
Oh no lava, Ohhh!
Imagination land is the best.
Oh this is not gonna be so interactive.
Hey look, the house of cards.
Oh wait, hang on just a minute.
Ah, your rocket. Yeahh!
I stached it in there for safe keeping and now it's gonna send Rylie to the moon.
Oh I'm sorry.
Great.
Ohhh I love imagination land.
Isn't it great? Amd there is always something new like...
Who the heck it that?!
Imaginary boyfriend.
I would die for Rylie.
Ah I've never seen him before.
I live in Canada.
Anyway, this way through preschool world. We're nearly to the train.
Rylie, here we come.
Ohhh!
This should be fun, new team, new friends.
These kids look pretty good, consider they're from San Fransisco.
Gotta go.
Okay, good luck sweetie.
Luck isn't gonna help us now, if she tries to use hockey island it's going down.
Which is why I've recalled every hockey memory I can think of.
One of these's gotta work in place of the core memory.
She's about to play. Hurry.
Aha we did it gang, it's working... Ahh!
Haha! No, no no.
It's like we don't learn anything.
That's it. No no no, free on your happy place.
Rylie what's wrong?
Let's go.
You are not gonna finish tryouts?
What's the point?
Hey, it will be alright, let's just...
Stop saying everything is gonna be alright!
Hockey!
Oh no no, she loves hockey.
She can't give up hockey!
Bing Bong we have to get to that station.
Sure thing, this way just pass crankpacker castle.
Hey, wierd! Cranckpacker castle used to be rigt here.
I wonder why they moved it.
Ah that's odd I would have sworn mouse was right here.
Hey, what's going on?!
Yeah yeah I don't know, we will have to come back.
Princess's dream world! Oh the stuffed animal hall of fame!
My rocket! Wait, Rylie and I were too used to that rocket, it's still have some song power left.
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Nooooo, you can't take my rocket to the dump.
Rylie and I are going to the moon.
Rylie can't be done with me!
Hey it's gonna be okay, we can fix this.
We just need to get back to headquarters, which way to the train station?
I had a whole trip planned for us.
Hey, who's ticklish , Ha? Here comes the tickle monster.
Hey Bing Bong look at this.. Bliah bliah!!
Oh here's a fun game, you playing to the train station and we all go there.
Wouldn't that be fun? Come on, let's go to the train station.
I'm sorry they took your rocket, they took something tht you loved.
It's gone ... forever
Sadness, don't make him feel worse.
Sorry. It's all I had left of Rylie.
I bet you and Rylie had great adventures.
Oh, they were wonderful.
Once we flew back in time, we had breakfast twice that day.
Sadness! It sounds amazing, I bet Rylie liked it.
Oh she did, we were best friends.
Yeah, it's sad.
I'm okay now.
Come on the train station is this way.
How did you do that?
I ... I don't know, he was sad so I listened to what ...
Hey! there is the train.
We made it, we're finally gonna get home.
Oh no these facts and opinions look so similar.
Don't worry about it, happens all the time.
On a scale of one to ten I give this day an F.
Well why don't we quit standing around and do something?
Like what genius? Like quitting, that's what I'm doing.
I'm sure it's the coward's way out but this coward is gonna survive.
Emotions can't quit genius.
I thought we were supposed to be keeping Rylie happy.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Aha, ho ho ho.
What is it? Oh nothing, just the best idea ever.
What? All the good core memories were made in Menasota
Here you go, we go back in Menasota and make more, Taraaa
Wait wait wait, you say we run away?!
Ah I wouldn't call it that. I would call it the happy core memory development program.
You can't be serious!
Hey, our life was perfect until mom and dad decided to move to San Franstate town
But it's just so drastic.
Need I remind you of how great things were there?
Our room, our backyard, our friends.
TripleDent gum will make you smile ... Did I ask for the gum commercial?!
Anyway it was better, that's my point.
Yeah, Rylie was happier in Menasota.
Wait, hold on shouldn't we just sleep on this or something?
Fine, let's sleep on it because I'm sure charley funfill times are just around the corner.
Hey hey why aren't we moving?
Rylie's gone for sleep, we're all on break.
You mean we're stuck here until morning?
Yeah, the train of thoughts doesn't run while she's asleep.
Oh, we can't wait that long.
How about we wake her up?
Sadness, that's ridiculous.
How could we possibly...
How about we wake her up?
Great idea, Joy. Thanks, come on.
Wow this place is huge.
Yeah, it looks so much smaller than I expected.
Wow! "I can fly" I love that one.
Rainbow unicorn! She's right there.
My friend says you're famous, she wants your autoraph.
No no, Sadness don't bother miss Unicorn okay?
Sorry, she's from out of town.
It's so embarassing, right?
I loved you in fairy dream adventure part seven, okay bye.
I love you.
Ha, I wonder what that means.
Ah well, let's go in.
Set up the room set. Today's memories are in, we gotta a lot of work here.
Rylie dumped her bestfriend, had a miserable day at school and quit hockey.
The writers are put together a killer's script
Just because Joy and Sadness are gone I have to do stupid dream duty.
Okay, how are we gonna wake her up?
Well she wakes up sometimes when she has a scary dream, we could scare her.
Scare her?! No no, she's been through enough already.
But Joy. Sadness you may know your way aroud here but I know Rylie.
We're gonna make her so happy, she'll wake up with exhilaration.
We'll exite her awake. Ah that never happened before.
Oh Rylie loves dogs, put this on.
I don't think that will work.
Bing Bong. Yeah?
Donlt let anything happen to these. Got it.
Hmmm add the reality distortion filter.
Love it, remember play to the camera everyone.
Rylie is the camera. Make up, get out of there.
We're on in five, four, three...
Hello, class. Before we begin today's pop quiz.
Yeah, she's one of bad address.
I want to introduce our new student, Rylie.
Would you like to stand up and introduce yourself?
And Rylie, my name is Rylie Anderson
I'm from Menasota and now I live here.
Euhh! look her teeth are falling out.
That's growth!
Teeth falling out...
Let me guess, we have no pence on.
Hey look she came to school with no pence on.
Ready? I don't think happy is going to work but if we scare her...
Just follow my lead, here we go.
park, park, park...
What is that?
Ahh what is going on?!
Ohhh let's party, dance
Ohhh party.
park park...
Joy this is not working.
Sadness, what are you doing?
Come back here.
It's just a dream, it's just a dream...
They're trying to wake her up, call security.
Hi Rylie it's me.
Bing Bong?!
Who is your friend who likes to play? Bing Bong...
Sadness, you are ruining this dream, you're scaring her.
But look, it's working
Wow!
They are not part of this dream, get them.
Stop right there.
Pin away, pin away.
Booohh! pick a part line.
You can't do this, I know somebody from the headquarters.
No, no no no...
there go the core memories.
Come on.
What is this place?
The subconscious.
That's where they take all the trouble makers.
Hmm how do we get in?
This is my hat, wait it says my hat?
That's what I wrote in my hat. What are you talking about?...
Hey you.
Oh, you cought us.
Get back in there. No escaping.
I don't like it here, it's where they keep Rylie's darkest fears.
Ahhhh! It's brocolli.
The stairs to the basement..
Grandma's vacuum cleaner.
Okay, come on.
Would you walk quiter?
I'm trying.
What's going? Candy wrappers?!
Bing Bong!
Joy!
There you are.
Shhhh!
It's Jangles.
Who's the birthday girl...
Do you have the core memories?
Yeah, all he cared about was the candy.
We're out of here.
Let's get to that train.
Wait! The train is not running, we still have to wake up Rylie.
But how?
Oh no!
Hey Sadness, did you hear about the party they were having?
Yeah, yes Joy isn't it a birthday party?
Did you say birthday?
There is cake and presents ... and games and balloons
Birthday!
Okay, follow us.
Nothing like a good scare to wake you up, right?
Okay but this is my handwriting.
No it isn't, it's my handriting. I wrote that.
Who's the birthday girl?
Come on let's go.
Hahaha we made it.
Guess who is on their way to headquarters?
We are.
What is going on?
He did it again.
We were naked and there was a dog, they laughed at us ..
There is Bing Bong and ...
You idiot! It was a dream!
This is ridicoulus.
We can't even get a goodnight sleep anymore.
Time to take action.
Stupid mom and dad, if they hadn't move us, none of this would have happened.
Who's with me?
Yeah, let's do it.
She took it, there is no turning back.
So how are we gonna get to Menasota from here?
Well why won't we go down to the elephant lot and ride an elephant?
Hey, that sounds nice.
We're taking the bus!
There is a bus leaving tomorrow, perfect.
A ticket costs money, how do we get money?
Mom's purse.
Ahhh you wouldn't!
Ah, but I would.
Where was it we saw it last?
TripleDent gum will make you...
Noooooo!
It's down stairs somewhere, mom and dad got us into this mess, they can pay to get us out.
How about this ha? Isn't it nice?
You can see everything from up here.
Look, there is inductive reasoning.
There is deja vu, there is language processing, there is deja vu.
There is critical thinking, there is deja vu .. and look at this guy's memories...
Hey, that was a good idea .. about scaring Rylie awake.
You're not so bad. Really?
Nice work.
Ah, I can't wait to get the old Rylie back, as soon as we get there I'm gonna fix this whole mess.
Wow is this Rylie? She's so big now, she won't fit in my rocket
how are we gonna get to the moon?!
Oh it's that time in the twisty tree, remember?
The hockey team showed up and mom and dad were there cheering.
Look at her, having fun and laughing.
Ahhh I love this one.
Hmmm I love that one too. Oh girl, now you're getting it.
Yeah, it was the day that Perry dogs lost the big playoff game
Rylie missed the winning shot, she felt awful, she wanted to quit.
Sorry, I went sad again, didn't I?
I'll tell you what ... we can keep working on that when we get back, okay?
Okay.
why did our moving van even go to texas?!
Multiple customers...
But you promised delivery on the fifth...
Aha..
Exuse me, isn't there anyway that you can rush it?
Honesty island!
Look out!
That was our way home, we lost another island, what is happening?!
Haven't you heard? Rylie is running away.
What?!
Wait wait, hang on guys are we really doing this?
I mean this is serious.
Look, we have no core memories.
You want Rylie to be happy? Let's get back to Menasota and make more.
Joy if we hurry we can still stop her.
Family island. Let's go.
Joy, it's too dangerous, we won't make it in time.
But that's our only way back!
A recall tube!
We can get recalled.
Have a great day, sweetheart.
See you after school monkey.
Woo woo woo
We love you.
Go run run goo
Sadness stop, you're hurting Rylie
Oh no, I did it again.
If you get in here, these core memories will get sad. I'm sorry.
Rylie needs to be happy.
Joy!
Joy, Joy what are you doing?
Would you stop it please?
Don't you get it Joy?!
We're stuck down here.
We're forgotten.
We used to play tag and stuff but things are different now since we moved...
Do you remember how she used to stick her tongue out when she was colouring?
I could listen to her stories all day.
I just wanted Rylie to be happy.
It was the day that Perry Dogs lost the big playoff game, Rylie missed the winning shot.
She felt awful, she wanted to quit
Sadness! Mom and dad! the team!
They came to help because of Sadness.
We have to get back up there.
Joy, we're stuck down here.
We might as well be on another planet.
Another planet!
Who's your friend who likes to play?
His rocket makes you yell horray!
Who's the best who likes....
Who's your friend who likes to play? Bing Bong Bing Bong...
Pop in.
Come on.
Come on Joy, one more time.
I gotta a feeling about this one.
Bing Bong Bing Bong.
His rocket makes you yell horray!...
Sing louder!
Wohoooo! Bing Bong we did it.
Bing Bong!
You made it!
Go, go save Rylie.
Take her to the moon for me, Okay?
I'll try Bing Bong.
I promise.
We're home.
Rylie!
I'll call her cell.
Oh this is terrible.
Wait is this one walking towards us? Let's cross the street.
It's mom, she's on to us. What do we do?
Rylie needs to get core memories, we keep going.
Sadness!
Sadness! Sadness, come on Sadness where are you?
Okay if I were Sadness were would I be?
Oh everything is awful and my legs don't work and
you have to drag me around...
Oh no it's mom again, what do we do?
This is madness, she shouldn't run away.
Let's get this idea out of her head.
Sadness Sadness!
Joy!
Wait Sadness.
Just let me go.
Rylie is better off without me.
Come back.
Hey you're saying your husband was blown away by an elephant.
Was he with anyone?
Yes, and there she is.
Hey, come back here.
Forget it Jake, it's cloud town.
Sadness!
I make everything worse.
Wait Sadness, we gotta get you back to...
Oh it's stuck!
Oh great! What, what do you mean it's stuck?!
No what? No no no
What is this?!
How do we stop it? I got it, make her feel scared
that will make her change her mind.
Brilliant! I know it's brilliant, do it.
It's not working, why isn't it woking?!
Let me try.
Let me do it.
Noo. Guys we can't make Rylie feel anything.
What have we done?!
Hey look at me, did you mean what you said before.
I would die for Rylie, I would die for Rylie.
Okay haircut, time to proove it.
I would die for Rylie... I would die for Rylie...
That's it, I've hold.
This is crazy, this is crazy...
No no, Joy be positive.
I'm positive this is crazy.
Now!
For Ryliiiee.
Joy!
Hang on.
I wish Joy was here.
It's Joy.
Stand back.
That worked.
Well what would you do if you're so smart?
I'd tell you but you're too dump to understand.
Of course your tiny brain is confused, I guess I'll have to
dump it down to your level. Sorry I don't speak moron as you but let me try.
We found this idea, now Rylie...
Joy you have to fix this, get up there.
Sadness, it's up to you.
Me?! Sadness! Sadness!
I can't Joy.
Yes you can, Rylie needs you.
Okay.
Wait stop.
I wanna get off.
Alright, thank you. We will.
Her teacher hasn't even seen Rylie all day.
What?! What was she wearing last? Do you remember...
Rylie! We were worried sick, were have you been? It's so late.
I know you don't want me to but ... I miss home.
I miss Menasota, you need me to be happy but ... I want my old friends and my hockey team. I wanna go home.
Please don't be mad. Oh sweetie, we're not mad.
You know what? I miss Menasota too. I miss the woods..
And the backyard where you used to play, spring lake where you learned to skate.
Come here.
Hey I'm liking this new view, friendship island expanded.
Gladly finally opened that friendly argument section.
I like the vampire tragic romance island.
Fashion island, everyone shut up.
Boyband island?! I hope that's just a phase.
Say what you want, I think it's all beautiful.
Alright here you go, your new expanded console is up and running.
Woahhhh!
Oh upgrade.
Hey, whoah oops!
Did I just do that?
Guys, what's puberty?
No it's probably not important.
I have access to the entire curse word library.
This new console is...
Sorry I did it again, my bad.
You go out there, you be agressive.
Not too agressive, you know you guys don't have to come every game!
Are you kidding? I'm not missing one.
Go Rylie. I gotta go.
Yeah mom and dad are pretty cool.
Guys of course they are but we can't show it.
She loved this, I told you it's a great idea.
Best idea he's had in a while, he's a really good guy.
Just in case.
Sorry.
Girl girl girl...
Okay, bye.
You ready? Yeah.
Let's play some hockey.
On her left, on her left.
Let's just try not get too smelly this time.
We've been trough a lot lately, that's for sure but we still love our girl.
She has great new friends, a great new house, things couldn't be better.
After all Rylie is twelve now, what could happen?
and who could tell me at what year San Fransisco was founded?
Anyone? Ohhh, how much more of this? 5 months, 2 weeks and 4 days until summer vacation.
then we're up to the bahamas with you know who.
Come fly with me Gargenia...
Ahhhh
Have a nice day.
What are we mad about? I don't know...
I know, totally
We were total frod, do you think they can see through us?
Of course not, we're wearing eye shadow.
Who's the birthday girl? Ha?
Hey, hello. Six years of drama school for this!
Okay this is fine, we just need to go to our happy place...
TripleDent gum will make you smile...
Translated by: Monika Ossama
I hope you enjoyed it :)